<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Theatre in Colonial South, Southeast, and East Asia</title>
 <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/"/>
 <updated>2020-08-15T13:24:53-04:00</updated>
 <id>http://localhost:4000</id>
 <author>
   <name>Rashna Nicholson</name>
   <email>rnich@hku.hk</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Missing Footprints: British musical comedy in colonial Hong Kong</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/hong%20kong/2020/08/14/vincent-chu/"/>
   <updated>2020-08-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/hong%20kong/2020/08/14/vincent-chu</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Musical theatre is one of the most popular theatre forms worldwide. Before its reign came a British precursor—musical comedy, which was world-famous in its own right, especially in what was known as the British Empire.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; Despite its popularity, it had been widely neglected in academia and had been relatively obscured in cultural history.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; Remnants of it are often ascribed to other forms of entertainment. Its music ‘survived as pub and parlour ballads’ and is associated with the music halls.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; More than a hundred plays were erroneously ascribed to its American cousin, musical theatre.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt; As an integral component of the British Empire’s past, Hong Kong is expected to have seen its fair share of visiting troupes of this late Victorian and Edwardian art form.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt; Therefore, the city would constitute a good starting point for tracking the footprints of this evanescent giant. In this investigation, I have attempted to document the traces of British musical comedy in colonial Hong Kong through archival research. The findings suggest its lack of success in colonial Hong Kong. Thus, I will attempt to discuss the disparity between the expected popularity and the historical absence of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the surface, colonial Hong Kong was a fertile soil for the theatre trade. Branded the Pearl of the Orient, it served as a nodal point of the British trading networks in Asia. One form of commodities traded amongst others at this nodal point was theatre. In corroboration with the discussion of the modern industrial theatre model during the Edwardian era, troupes from the West indeed valued Hong Kong as a ‘new market [with] potential for profit maximization.’&lt;a href=&quot;#ref6&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt; This proposition is exemplified by the competition for venues between Willard’s American Musical Comedy and Opera Company and ‘a troupe of high-class and most accomplished Italian artists.’&lt;a href=&quot;#ref7&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt; The Italian troupe intended to leave the Philippines for Hong Kong and perform at the Theatre Royal, City Hall during the window between the two visits of Willard’s company. To monopolize the year at Theatre Royal, Willard booked the venue for October despite the company’s arrival in November. The news article emphasized Hong Kong as ‘fresh-pots’ and that the Italian troupe ‘would have made a deal of money judging from past experiences.’&lt;a href=&quot;#ref8&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt; There is no doubt therefore that the theatre trade in colonial Hong Kong was profitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, theatre was crucial to the diasporic community in Hong Kong. From a general perspective, theatre performances allow diasporic communities to ‘survive culturally and socially.’&lt;a href=&quot;#ref9&quot;&gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt; For the British and other European diasporic communities in colonies, theatre performances ‘provided a meeting place where [they] came together to constitute [themselves] as a community.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref10&quot;&gt;[10]&lt;/a&gt; This function of theatre performances is evident in the reportage of the opening night of Zorilla Musical Comedy Comedy’s &lt;em&gt;In Gay Paree&lt;/em&gt; in 1905. It clashed with the Governor’s Birthday Ball, which ‘kept a large number of people away’&lt;a href=&quot;#ref11&quot;&gt;[11]&lt;/a&gt; and left it with a “meagre” house’.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref12&quot;&gt;[12]&lt;/a&gt; Possibly as a gesture of courtesy, the Governor attended another performance by the company and his ‘distinguished patronage’ was advertised in the press on that day.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref13&quot;&gt;[13]&lt;/a&gt; It not only hinted that itinerant troupes had a primarily British (or European) diasporic patronage in Hong Kong. More importantly, it revealed the respect or enthusiasm this patronage had for theatre performances as exemplified by the Governor’s patronage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the British diaspora, British musical comedy had more to offer than other genres. It was an instrument of cultural imperialism, which ‘served as a lifeline to the home country’ and allowed the British diaspora to achieve cultural synchronization with their compatriots in Britain.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref14&quot;&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt; As described in Len Platt’s &lt;em&gt;Musical Comedy on the West End Stage, 1890—1939&lt;/em&gt;, British musical comedy was more socially engaged than ‘other forms of late Victorian and Edwardian theatre’ (20). By engaging with issues pertinent to the British society, such as modernity and national identity, British musical comedy served as a ‘vehicle for British ideologies … that [gave] voice to their collective expression as a popular articulation of society and values.’&lt;a href=&quot;#ref15&quot;&gt;[15]&lt;/a&gt; The British diaspora could learn and resonate with the shared sentiments and opinions of the British society in the face of ‘British’ social issues at the turn of the century through British musical comedy. The resonance was strong enough for the Hong Kong Philharmonic Orchestra to stage their own production of the British play &lt;em&gt;The Arcadians&lt;/em&gt; in 1937, which was the earliest record of a local musical comedy production in Hong Kong.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref16&quot;&gt;[16]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite these favourable factors, British musical comedy did not thrive in Hong Kong. There were several factors that could have contributed to this phenomenon with the difficulties in talent recruitment being front and centre. British musical comedy faced many production difficulties. Itinerant troupes had to maximize their profits. The specific production requirement of this novel form prompted musical company troupes to throw in other genres in their repertoire. For instance, the Banvard included a revue, the operetta &lt;em&gt;Katja, the Dancer&lt;/em&gt; (which was misidentified as musical comedy), and two American musical comedies in its 1928 season.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref17&quot;&gt;[17]&lt;/a&gt; The Henry Dallas Musical Company was an exception that had performed a season in Hong Kong with a repertoire comprising only British musical comedies.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref18&quot;&gt;[18]&lt;/a&gt; The most prominent difficulty lay in the recruitment of talent. British musical comedy was a departure from the forms of music theatre prior to its conception. Unlike the variety-natured musical halls, a musical play had a continuous narrative. Unlike operetta, it required ‘more natural styles of performance.’&lt;a href=&quot;#ref19&quot;&gt;[19]&lt;/a&gt; As opposed to operetta’s focus on ‘historical romanticism’, British musical comedy was concerned with ‘modernity’ as previously iterated.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref20&quot;&gt;[20]&lt;/a&gt; British musical comedy could be considered a balance between the ‘high art’ of operetta and the ‘common humour’ of music halls. It required realist actors who sang instead of full-fledged singers.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref21&quot;&gt;[21]&lt;/a&gt; This novelty could be an uncertainty for the itinerant troupes. It was more cost-effective to recruit performers from the more traditional forms and staged those forms during tours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, there were other difficulties in the recruitment of talent. The popularity of the form was short-lived for roughly twenty-five years and was struggling before World War I.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref22&quot;&gt;[22]&lt;/a&gt; As realistic as British musical comedy intended to be, it painted the British society in an image of ‘upbeat celebration of modernity’ and ‘[a] naïve assertion of faith in progress and social inclusion.’&lt;a href=&quot;#ref23&quot;&gt;[23]&lt;/a&gt; It failed to capture the insecurities of the British public in the pre-war era and was deemed ‘astonishingly dissonant and quite out of touch in the inter-war period.’&lt;a href=&quot;#ref24&quot;&gt;[24]&lt;/a&gt; The once-progressive form was no longer fashionable and relevant to the sentiments of its British patrons, who started to take a liking to revue. As revue took the crown as the new fashionable musical theatre, talent in Britain began to leave musical comedy for revue.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref25&quot;&gt;[25]&lt;/a&gt; The talent pool became smaller for British musical comedy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although joining itinerant troupes was an option for musical comedy practitioners, the uncertainties associated with touring were dissuasive. In Kathryn Hansen’s article ‘Mapping Melodrama’, the account of the Australian troupe ‘Sarah Lewis’ Dramatic Company’ documented the deaths of several members of this family business due to the harsh conditions during tours.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref26&quot;&gt;[26]&lt;/a&gt; The uncertainties were mostly financial, nonetheless. As troupes often travelled around different colonies, they would be faced with varied climate conditions. For instance, rain would dissuade the theatregoers from attending performances but ‘the rainy season varied from country to country,’&lt;a href=&quot;#ref27&quot;&gt;[27]&lt;/a&gt; Therefore, most tours in Southeast Asia were initially seasonal to avoid the rainy season.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref28&quot;&gt;[28]&lt;/a&gt; Despite employing counter-measures such as putting up ‘rainproof tents’ in later performances, some were occasionally cancelled due to the overwhelming weather.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref29&quot;&gt;[29]&lt;/a&gt; The competition between Willard’s company and the Italian troupe for Theatre Royal best exemplified the financial risk of touring. After its failure in securing a venue, the Italian troupe had to cancel its tour in Hong Kong and disbanded as a result.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref30&quot;&gt;[30]&lt;/a&gt; An alternative was to recruit local talent during the tour, but it would be hardly viable for touring in Hong Kong. The earliest documentation of a local musical comedy production was in 1937, near the end of the genre’s relevance as suggested by Len Platt.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref31&quot;&gt;[31]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From what I could gather, there was a talent shortage that placed British musical comedy at a disadvantage during its touring days in Hong Kong. However, the favourable conditions for the theatre trade might have in turn benefitted its coevals in thriving financially and welcomed the emergence of film. There are a few perspectives to consider for further investigation. The transformation of musical comedy from the stage to the silver screen was certainly crucial and deserves investigation. As the genre was a recreation of the British sentiments and the society, it was a product of realism and glamour. It is worth looking into the theatrical technologies of colonial Hong Kong and examining whether they were up to the task of producing British musical comedy. Despite its evanescence, British musical comedies were incorporated into music halls’ programmes.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref32&quot;&gt;[32]&lt;/a&gt; It might have survived as artistic heritage in current forms of theatre in Hong Kong as well. It is worth investigating its artistic impact in morphing theatre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;appendix&quot;&gt;Appendix&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vchu1.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;50%&amp;quot;; style=&amp;quot;margin: 0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Appendix 1. ‘THE HENDRY DALLAS MUSICAL COMEDY COMPANY,’ &lt;em&gt;Soutch China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 25 February 1904, 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vchu2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;50%&amp;quot;; style=&amp;quot;margin: 0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Appendix 2. ‘HENDRY DALLAS MUSICAL COMEDY COMPANY,’ &lt;em&gt;Soutch China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 29 February 1904, 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vchu3.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;50%&amp;quot;; style=&amp;quot;margin: 0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Appendix 3. ‘THE HENDRY DALLAS MUSICAL COMEDY COMPANY,’ &lt;em&gt;Soutch China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 26 February 1904, 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; Len Platt, &lt;em&gt;Musical Comedy on the West End Stage, 1890-1939&lt;/em&gt; (NYC: Springer, 2004), 9.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; Ibid, 10-2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; Ibid, 10-1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt; Ibid, 13-4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt; Ibid, 9.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref6&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt; Christopher Balme, and Nic Leonhardt, ‘Introduction: Theatrical Trade Routes,’ &lt;em&gt;Journal of Global Theatre History&lt;/em&gt; 1, no. 1 (2016): 1-9, 4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref7&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;The Hong Kong Telegraph&lt;/em&gt;, 28 September 1888, 2, NPTG18880928.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref8&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt; Ibid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref9&quot;&gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt; Balme and Leonhardt, 5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref10&quot;&gt;[10]&lt;/a&gt; Tobias Becker, ‘Entertaining the empire: Theatrical touring companies and amateur dramatics in colonial India,’ &lt;em&gt;The Historical Journal&lt;/em&gt; 57, no. 3 (2014): 699-725, 721.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref11&quot;&gt;[11]&lt;/a&gt; ‘ZORILLA MUSICAL COMEDY CO,’ &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 15 November 1905, 7&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/1554629754?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/1554629754?accountid=14548&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref12&quot;&gt;[12]&lt;/a&gt; ‘THE ZORILLA MUSICAL COMEDY COMPANY,’ &lt;em&gt;The Hong Kong Telegraph&lt;/em&gt;, 15 November 1905, 5, NPTG19051115.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref13&quot;&gt;[13]&lt;/a&gt; ‘ZORILLA MUSICAL COMEDY CO,’ &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 20 November 1905, 3, https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/1498566768?accountid=14548.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref14&quot;&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt; Becker, 701.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref15&quot;&gt;[15]&lt;/a&gt; Platt, 20.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref16&quot;&gt;[16]&lt;/a&gt; ‘ARCADY IN HONGKONG: PHILHARMONIC SOCIETY’S SUCCESS WITH MUSICAL COMEDY LOCAL TALENT TRIUMPHS,’ &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 16 December 1937, 8. https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/1759907747?accountid=14548.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref17&quot;&gt;[17]&lt;/a&gt; ‘THE BANVARD MUSICAL COMEDY CO,’ &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 8 February 1928, 5&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/1754300333?accountid=14548.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref18&quot;&gt;[18]&lt;/a&gt; See Appendix 1-3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref19&quot;&gt;[19]&lt;/a&gt; Platt, 29.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref20&quot;&gt;[20]&lt;/a&gt; Ibid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref21&quot;&gt;[21]&lt;/a&gt; Ibid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref22&quot;&gt;[22]&lt;/a&gt; Ibid, 126.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref23&quot;&gt;[23]&lt;/a&gt; Ibid, 128.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref24&quot;&gt;[24]&lt;/a&gt; Ibid, 128.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref25&quot;&gt;[25]&lt;/a&gt; Ibid, 131.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref26&quot;&gt;[26]&lt;/a&gt; Kathryn Hansen, ‘Mapping melodrama: Global theatrical circuits, Parsi theater, and the rise of the social,’ &lt;em&gt;BioScope: South Asian Screen Studies&lt;/em&gt; 7, no. 1 (2016): 1-30, 8-9, 11.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref27&quot;&gt;[27]&lt;/a&gt; Nadi Tofighian, ‘Mapping “the whirligig of amusements” in colonial Southeast Asia.’&lt;em&gt;Journal of Southeast Asian Studies&lt;/em&gt; 49, no. 2 (2018): 277, 294.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref28&quot;&gt;[28]&lt;/a&gt; Ibid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref29&quot;&gt;[29]&lt;/a&gt; Ibid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref30&quot;&gt;[30]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;The Hong Kong Telegraph&lt;/em&gt;, 28 September 1888, 2, NPTG18880928.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref31&quot;&gt;[31]&lt;/a&gt; ‘ARCADY IN HONGKONG,; &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref32&quot;&gt;[32]&lt;/a&gt; Platt, 127.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;Bibliography&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;‘ARCADY IN HONGKONG: PHILHARMONIC SOCIETY’S SUCCESS WITH MUSICAL COMEDY LOCAL TALENT TRIUMPHS.’ &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 16 December 1937, 8&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/1759907747?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/1759907747?accountid=14548.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Balme, Christopher, and Nic Leonhardt. ‘Introduction: Theatrical Trade Routes.’ &lt;em&gt;Journal of Global Theatre History&lt;/em&gt; 1, no. 1 (2016): 1-9.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;‘THE BANVARD MUSICAL COMEDY CO.’ &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 8 February 1928, 5&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/1754300333?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/1754300333?accountid=14548.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Becker, Tobias. ‘Entertaining the empire: Theatrical touring companies and amateur dramatics in colonial India.’ &lt;em&gt;The Historical Journal&lt;/em&gt; 57, no. 3 (2014): 699-725.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Hansen, Kathryn. ‘Mapping melodrama: Global theatrical circuits, Parsi theater, and the rise of the social.’ &lt;em&gt;BioScope: South Asian Screen Studies&lt;/em&gt; 7, no. 1 (2016): 1-30.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;‘THE HENRY DALLAS MUSICAL COMEDY COMPANY.’ &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 25 February 1904, 3&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/1498463570?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/1498463570?accountid=14548.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;‘THE HENRY DALLAS MUSICAL COMEDY COMPANY.’ &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 26 February 1904, 3&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/1499873253?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/1499873253?accountid=14548.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;‘HENRY DALLAS MUSICAL COMEDY COMPANY.’ &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 29 February 1904, 3&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/1498464257?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/1498464257?accountid=14548.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Platt, Len. &lt;em&gt;Musical Comedy on the West End Stage, 1890-1939&lt;/em&gt;. NYC: Springer, 2004.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Hong Kong Telegraph&lt;/em&gt;, 28 September 1888, 2. NPTG18880928.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Tofighian, Nadi. ‘Mapping ‘the whirligig of amusements’ in colonial Southeast Asia.’ &lt;em&gt;Journal of Southeast Asian Studies&lt;/em&gt; 49, no. 2 (2018): 277.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;‘THE ZORILLA MUSICAL COMEDY COMPANY.’ &lt;em&gt;The Hong Kong Telegraph&lt;/em&gt;, 15 November 1905, 5, NPTG19051115.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;‘ZORILLA MUSICAL COMEDY CO.’ &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 15 November 1905, 7&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/1554629754?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/1554629754?accountid=14548.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;‘ZORILLA MUSICAL COMEDY CO.’ &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 20 November 1905, 3&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/1498566768?accountid=14548.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>English Theatre as a Colonial Project in Hong Kong</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/hong%20kong/2020/08/14/sun-ho-kim/"/>
   <updated>2020-08-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/hong%20kong/2020/08/14/sun-ho-kim</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My essay focuses on the 1940-50s theatre of colonial Hong Kong, and the messy discourse analysis that erupts from the unyielding archives of the &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post&lt;/em&gt; (SCMP). While I attempt to show that a framework of orient/other can become a cast set too soon when considering the role of theatre and the impact of ENSA, a military entertainment service, I find it fruitful to preface the discussion with a figure named Micheal Fong and his tenuous connection to H.J Mackinder. Kirsten Guest recalls to us the 1913 hearing for the passage of the National Theatre Act, which would subsidize a theatre in London to produce revered English plays such as those of Shakespeare. In it the house speaker at the time, she summarises, argues that at the “level of empire, a National Theatre would reinforce the sense of racial identity between colonies and their parent nations.”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; House Speaker Mackinder continues: “If we wish to retain a language which shall be, when spoken, and not merely when written, then … you must have it heard as expressing its literature in some such central position.”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; Of course, the act was not passed until 1949, two years after his death, but he might find some comfort in knowing that a mere 6 years after its passing, a citizen in the British colony of Hong Kong by the name of Michael Fong wrote this to the editor of the South China Morning Post:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Sir—Sometime last month there was a recorded version of Shakespeare’s “Romeo and Juliet” over Radio Hong Kong. I wonder whether it is possible for Radio Hong Kong to broadcast it once more as I missed it last time. Recorded versions of the great tragedies of Shakespeare—King Lear, Othello, Hamlet and Macbeth will be very much appreciated.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;English theatre’s role in colonial Hong Kong, then, can be understood as the import of English culture and language into the everyday of citizens. It’s role as a form of education can be seen in the Diocesan Girls School’s presentation of two plays in 1951,&lt;a href=&quot;#ref4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt; as well as the Governor’s attendance of a University of Hong Kong (HKU) produced play ten years prior.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt; Plays were even written explicitly for the instruction of English to non-natives.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref6&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/shkim1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;margin: 0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figure 1. SCMP, 18 Jan 1956, 5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the role of theatre is not limited to the domain of education. Theatre, as a cultural highway between the colony and the mainland, serves not only to transport cultural commodities to the locals, but also to the military personnel stationed in Hong Kong. While interpreting theatre as a tool of orientalism while focusing on the discourse of power between the ‘local/mainland’ as well as its intersections with class in colonial Hong Kong is fruitful, it risks papering over the uneven development of English theatre in Hong Kong as well as attributing a false power to the British government. Said’s line of questioning: “Who writes? For whom is the writing being done? In what circumstances?”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref7&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt; is still relevant of course. But when he writes that “culture . . . is to be found operating within civil society, where the influence of ideas, of institutions, and of other persons works not through domination, but through what Gramsci calls consent,”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref8&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt; he prescribes a rigid frame of interpretation that does not adequately accommodate the shifty, vacillating nature of hegemony. Mackinder envisioned that Shakespeare was the right nail for pinning the English language to a high standard of shared culture and linguistic norm. But he did not predict that it would be utilized as a remedy for homesickness. Indeed, the first theatrical plays in Hong Kong were put on by homesick soldiers who started the Hong Kong Amateur Dramatic Club in 1844.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref9&quot;&gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the focus of his essay will primarily be directed towards the 1940-50s, when the Entertainments National Service Association, or ENSA, was founded by two theatre directors, Basil Dean and Leslie Henson. Starting from January 1946, it ran for seventeen months before being superseded by the CSE (combined service entertainment). While it was running, they hosted theatre troupes from abroad as well as produced and starred servicemen from the British military. At the time, it was noted for its popularity with both “civilians and servicemen alike” and boasted a total of 94000 audience members over its lifetime.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref10&quot;&gt;[10]&lt;/a&gt; As Becker observes, this is not an unusual or particularly noteworthy arrangement: “Most colonial Britons, whether soldiers, administrators, or businessmen, lived in close-knit diasporic communities.”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref11&quot;&gt;[11]&lt;/a&gt; Theatre, as Becker argues, constituted a public space wherein diasporic Britons abroad could socialize and anchor themselves to the culture that they left behind at home. The continuation of a cultural history that extended back to Shakespeare helped to solidify the faraway colonial territory of Hong Kong as a legitimate participant of the empire. The intersection between education and entertainment is not tangential to the development of theatre in Hong Kong either. If the act of going to the theatre was a performance that indicated a level of civilization, then bringing it to Hong Kong could be thought of as a natural extension of the colonial project. The Said-ian idea of orientalism as an othering process by which the central orient gains in this unequal relationship, a “cultural contestant, and one of its [the occident]’s deepest and most recurring images of the Other.”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref12&quot;&gt;[12]&lt;/a&gt; The difference between the colony and the mainland, as marked by their linguistic differences and lack of English theatre, as well as the sameness (Cantonese opera), produced a space in which both diaspora and nationalism were accommodated. For example, funds gathered from a Chinese theatrical play could be directed to the B.W.O.F war fund, and even legitimized by the presence of the governor in the audience.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref13&quot;&gt;[13]&lt;/a&gt; On the other hand, Christmas could be celebrated by an eclectic performance of a hybrid musician who combined “modern” sounds with the traditional instruments of China. It is to be a medley, with theatre and classical music mixed in as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/shkim2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;margin: 0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figure 2. SCMP, 22 Dec 1946, 6.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This uneasy coexistence between both Chinese and English theatre highlights the key tension in the discussion of theatre in 1940-50s Hong Kong: borders. Theatre is delineated by physical borders that disconnect the public from the audience (via a dark, harshly lit room), audience from the stage (elevated wooden platforms and comfy chairs), the actor from each other (by bright spotlights) and even audiences from audiences (best seats in the house). This lends itself to an analysis of the power dynamics that are always interested in how certain groups are atomized and certain individuals, homogenized. As Michel Foucault writes: “the spatialising description of discursive realities gives on to the analysis of related effects of power.”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref14&quot;&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt; In other words, the tool of discourse analysis, language, biases us towards certain metaphorical understandings of power. The very same “instruments which will enable you to fight on that terrain” (Foucault, 1980, 65), also trap us in a language game. In a Lakoff-ian sense, “Argument is War” or in our case, “Space is Nation.” So, when touring companies come to Hong Kong&lt;a href=&quot;#ref15&quot;&gt;[15]&lt;/a&gt; to entertain servicemen and Brits abroad, they are bringing with them a cultural capital to invest and territorialize a small building in the colony and transform it for a short moment into London. It also means that certain plays can be excluded as well. For example, German and Japanese plays were banned—a symbolic way of bordering off the colony from other hostile powers and their cultural reach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/shkim3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;margin: 0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figure 3. SCMP, 3 Mar 1950, 9.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Equally as important as the import of plays into Hong Kong, are the borders that form once admittance is formalized. As advertisements state, any local that wants access must be accompanied by servicemen- as a plus one if you will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/shkim4.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;margin: 0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figure 4. SCMP, 28 May 1946, 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This atomizes the colony of Hong Kong into two different sets of people, civilians and military servicemen, theatre goers and non-theatre goers, locals and expats. At the same time, it homogenizes by the same token, the military into one cohesive unit that has the exclusive right to protect, patrol and enforce these borders—a walking checkpoint of sorts into the culture of the United Kingdom. These borders were a permeable and flexible reality that kept changing and shifting to reflect the varying needs of the colony at the time. For example, at times, civilians were not allowed access at all due to a shortage of supply or an overflowing demand—at times civilians were allowed to book tickets without the permission of servicemen. In this regard, it is useful to turn to Raymond Williams framework of the hegemonic:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A lived hegemony is always a process. It is not, except analytically, a system or a structure. It is a realised complex of experiences, relationships and activities, with specific and changing pressures and limits.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref16&quot;&gt;[16]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than trying to understand the borderality of theatre as simple binaries that separate two disparate groups, utilizing the imagery of territory while still being open to sudden changes and resistance to the flow of power can allow a more fruitful understanding of theatre in colonial times. This is exemplified by Micheal Fong, the mystery man who wrote the editor’s note on SCMP. Bearing an almost stereotypically diasporic name, he enquires about the possibility of accessing through radio, an old English play that hints us towards an at least upper-middle class standing. The technology is there now to reach across oceans and scroll backwards in time- and yet we must still remain open to the possibility that our Micheal is a second-generation white man, or a well-educated local. While inconsequential to the larger discussion of theatre as a colonial project, the elusive figure of Micheal would have determined at least the tone of my essay. Archival studies on the past always work within the limitations of ambiguities and it is difficult to say for certain how or why theatre was produced in Hong Kong during the 1940-50s- but remaining open to the possibility of surprise and misinterpretation hopefully leads to a more honest discourse analysis of theatre during this time. Mr. Fong, I hope you got to enjoy your Shakespeare play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; Kristen Guest, “Culture, Class, and Colonialism: the Struggle for an English National Theatre, 1879–1913,” &lt;em&gt;Journal of Victorian Culture&lt;/em&gt; 11, no. 2 (2006): 281-300, 281.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; “National Theatre in London,” United Kingdom, &lt;em&gt;Parliamentary Debates&lt;/em&gt;, House of Commons, 23 April 1913, vol 52, cc454-95 (Halford McKinder, MP). https://api.parliament.uk/historic-hansard/people/sir-halford-mackinder/index.html.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 12 Feb 1955, 14.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 16 Dec 1951 19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 24 Mar 1941, 14.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref6&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 18 Jan 1956, 5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref7&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt; Edward W. Said, “Opponents, audiences, constituencies, and community,” &lt;em&gt;Critical Inquiry&lt;/em&gt; 9, no. 1 (1982): 1-26, 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref8&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt; Said, &lt;em&gt;Orientalism: Western Conceptions of the Orient, with a new Afterword&lt;/em&gt; (Harmondsworth, England: Penguin Books, 1995), 7.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref9&quot;&gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt; Kevin J. Wetmore Jr, Siyuan Liu, and Erin B. Mee, &lt;em&gt;Modern Asian theatre and performance 1900-2000&lt;/em&gt; (London/NYC: A&amp;amp;C Black, 2014), 251.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref10&quot;&gt;[10]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 7 July 1947 4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref11&quot;&gt;[11]&lt;/a&gt; Tobias Becker, “Entertaining the empire: theatrical touring companies and amateur dramatics in colonial India,” &lt;em&gt;The Historical Journal&lt;/em&gt;, 57 no.3 699-725, 699.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref12&quot;&gt;[12]&lt;/a&gt; Said, &lt;em&gt;Orientalism&lt;/em&gt;, 131.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref13&quot;&gt;[13]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 17 Jan 1940, 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref14&quot;&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt; Michel Foucault, &lt;em&gt;Power/Knowledge&lt;/em&gt; (London: Harvester Wheatsheaf, 1980), 71.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref15&quot;&gt;[15]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 19 Jan 1947, 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref16&quot;&gt;[16]&lt;/a&gt; Raymond Williams, &lt;em&gt;Marxism and literature&lt;/em&gt; (Oxford/NYC: Oxford University Press, 1977), 112.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;Bibliography&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“National Theatre in London.” United Kingdom, &lt;em&gt;Parliamentary Debates&lt;/em&gt;, House of Commons, 23 April 1913, vol 52, cc454-95 (Halford McKinder, MP). https://api.parliament.uk/historic-hansard/people/sir-halford-mackinder/index.html.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Becker, Tobias. “Entertaining the empire: theatrical touring companies and amateur dramatics in colonial India.” &lt;em&gt;The Historical Journal&lt;/em&gt; 57, no.3 699-725.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Foucault, Michel. &lt;em&gt;Power/Knowledge&lt;/em&gt;. London: Harvester Wheatsheaf, 1980.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Guest, Kristen. “Culture, Class, and Colonialism: the Struggle for an English National Theatre, 1879–1913.” &lt;em&gt;Journal of Victorian Culture&lt;/em&gt; 11, no. 2 (2006): 281-300.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Said, Edward W. &lt;em&gt;Orientalism: Western Conceptions of the Orient, with a new Afterword&lt;/em&gt;. Harmondsworth, England: Penguin Books, 1995.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;———.”Opponents, audiences, constituencies, and community.” &lt;em&gt;Critical Inquiry&lt;/em&gt; 9, no. 1 (1982): 1-26.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Wetmore Jr, Kevin J., Siyuan Liu, and Erin B. Mee. &lt;em&gt;Modern Asian theatre and performance 1900-2000&lt;/em&gt;. London/NYC: A&amp;amp;C Black, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Williams, Raymond. &lt;em&gt;Marxism and literature&lt;/em&gt;. Oxford/NYC: Oxford University Press, 1977.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A Chinese Honeymoon—Fetishizing China on Stage</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/hong%20kong/singapore/2020/08/14/sharon-k-yuen/"/>
   <updated>2020-08-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/hong%20kong/singapore/2020/08/14/sharon-k-yuen</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Chinese Honeymoon&lt;/em&gt;, a musical produced by British company Henry Dallas Musical Comedy Company, was deemed one of the most popular musicals of its times.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; A close examination of the musical itself, the agents involved and the reception towards the show reveals the complex nature of how the East is depicted by the West in the 1900s between the colonizers and colonized societies, particularly that of the United Kingdom, Hong Kong and Singapore.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; This paper argues that the show reveals a certain fetishizing of the idea of the East from the eyes of the West.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focusing on the show as produced in the United Kingdom, Hong Kong and Singapore, this paper will first discuss the content of the show, its reception and its commercial success to reveal the show’s celebrated yet fetishized depiction of an imagined China. After which, we will examine how the show was received and reviewed across different locations, specifically in Hong Kong and Singapore. Throughout, this paper will pay careful attention to how the agents interact within and about the show. It becomes important to consider both the cast and the crew, and, more significantly, the audience and the newspapers reporting on the show to reveal how individual identity is represented and seen through the theatrical event. The global theatrical and commercial reception will be discussed to reveal the power the conceptualization of the Oriental had across the theatrical, and hence, real world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-success&quot;&gt;The Success&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Henry Dallas Musical Comedy Company derived significant theatrical and commercial success with the musical &lt;em&gt;A Chinese Honeymoon&lt;/em&gt;. A review of the show staged in the United Kingdom, published soon after the first showing of the musical on Monday October 10th 1800, lauded the premier with glowing praise, remarking that its first performance proved “an exceedingly good one” with its acting deserving of the “highest praise”, concluding that the show is “well mounted and admirably dressed.”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; The success of the show is evident in the number of times it was put up, having gone beyond a thousand shows at the Strand Theatre and attracted returning audience members who had grown to love seeing the show live.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt; By the 923rd consecutive show, it had already broken the theatre’s record of having a musical play be consecutively put up at the same location.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt; The Strand Theatre’s last show of the musical was numbered as the 1075th show, with the profits not short of six figures and well over the profits made in another famous musical &lt;em&gt;The Belle of New York&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref6&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt; The show was later staged at the Theatre Royal and was attended by “a large audience”.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref7&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt; Notably, the newspaper remarked that famously-named individuals were also in attendance, such as “His Excellency and Mrs. May”.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref8&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt; Similarly, the audience was reported to have been found giving “repeated applause” during the curtain call for many of the cast members.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref9&quot;&gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt; The importance and success of the play in the United Kingdom becomes immediately evident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disregarding the local success in the United Kingdom, the musical proved a hit worldwide. The mere fact that the Company travelled so wildly via the Norddeutscher liner &lt;em&gt;Konig Sin Luise&lt;/em&gt; is a good indication of its popularity.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref10&quot;&gt;[10]&lt;/a&gt; Some of the places that the Company had been to included Sri Lanka, India, Singapore and Hong Kong.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref11&quot;&gt;[11]&lt;/a&gt; Even though the Company performed multiple musical comedies with each tour at each location, &lt;em&gt;Chinese Honeymoon&lt;/em&gt; drew a significant amount of attention, with advertisements and reviews written by the local press in both Singapore and in Hong Kong. The show’s success was evident by its global spread, and, equally as important, its economic success. In 1904, the musical was reported to have yielded 60,000 pounds of clear profits, rendering it a “really successfully play”, with the authors’ share of gold reflected to be on a “regal scale”.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref12&quot;&gt;[12]&lt;/a&gt; Hence, it is undeniable that the ideas that the musical propagated and the world that it represented would easily be taken and spread around the world through such tours, making it significant for us to consider what exactly &lt;em&gt;Chinese Honeymoon&lt;/em&gt; depicted as a honeymoon in China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-show&quot;&gt;The Show&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The musical is set in a fictional, but clearly Chinese, location called Ylang Ylang, where an old-fashioned “Emperor” demands that couples found kissing must be married within 6 hours.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref13&quot;&gt;[13]&lt;/a&gt; The plots rests upon the protagonists of the show, Mr. Pineapple and his wife, a British couple who, “instead of spending their honeymoon in good old England”, opted to “invade the Yellow Man’s Territory.”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref14&quot;&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt; The rising action of the show depends on Mr. Pineapple becoming “compromised” by Chinese girls and Mrs. Pineapple taking revenge by “flirting with the pig-tailed brethren.”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref15&quot;&gt;[15]&lt;/a&gt; As seen through the words quoted from the archives to describe the actions of the West as taking over the actions of the East, such as the active verb of “invade”, a clear narrative of “them”—the East and “us”—the West is delivered through the show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lack of understanding of what it truly means to live in the East can be seen in the stereotypical and meaningless choice of names for the Chinese characters, such as Chippee Chop, Soo-Soo, Yen-Yen, Sing-sing. The fact that the cast is entirely Caucasian brings another issue to the table of representation of who is representing whom and brings the issue of yellow face into question. The same can be said of the lyrical content of the show, such as the first song, titled “In the days of the ancient long ago in a quaint little Chinese town” performed by Soo-Soo and the chorus.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref16&quot;&gt;[16]&lt;/a&gt; Anne Veronica Witchard notes that the lyrics of the musical, such as “chop, chop, chow, chow,/ sing song, sow, sow” are “unremittingly silly”, with “nonsense words” and “strange sounds of an incomprehensible and impossible language”.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref17&quot;&gt;[17]&lt;/a&gt; China, as represented in Chinese Honeymoon, then, is not a real location, but a fictionalized one. All these features point towards a level of ignorance and idealization of what it means to live in the East. Indeed, a review of the show aptly captures the culture of viewing the East as an exotic location: “Of late years we have had a succession of musical plays with rich and glowing Far Eastern setting. They have had a phenomenal popularity, but strangely enough the interest in the songs and daughters of the Flowerly Land never flags.”[18]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idealization in the musical of China, Chinatown and Chinese people as “quaint” and exotic demonstrates that a problematic phenomenon exists of the West infantalizing what it means to live in the East. The British musical and newspaper, and hence likely its audience and its consumers, viewed themselves as, at least, different, if not superior, to Chinese people. The notion of the West being superior to the Chinese can be seen in the many ways in which the musical depicts China as a strange, foreign and potentially barbaric place with unexplained customs and rules. The judgmental lens bring to mind what Edward Said argues about Orientalism in that “the Oriental becomes more Oriental, the Westerner more Western.”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref19&quot;&gt;[19]&lt;/a&gt; Similarly, scholar Dongshen Chang notes that there is a paradox of presence and absence of Chinese-ness in the British representations of China on stage – there was constant attention to China that deviated from China’s own representations of itself.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref20&quot;&gt;[20]&lt;/a&gt; Heidi Holder argues that such stereotypical plots of melodrama and colonial characters enact “an imperialist expansion of British culture.”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref21&quot;&gt;[21]&lt;/a&gt; It becomes clear then that, from Chinese Honeymoon, there was a divergence between how the musical sees the East and what the East actually is like – the East is exoticized in the musical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-tour--people&quot;&gt;The Tour &amp;amp; People&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ironically, even though the musical itself fetishizes the East, the tours of the musical in the East appeared to not have been met with much resistance or criticism in the newspaper archives. The show’s stereotypes are acknowledged but brushed aside by most reviews. In a review in the Hong Kong Weekly Press, the show was described as “light and amusing, and the music tuneful and gay”, so that it was “easy to understand” its popularity and commercial success.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref22&quot;&gt;[22]&lt;/a&gt; In Singapore, the show’s problematic representation of Chinese people is ignored, with a review merely describing the show as “a couple hours of light amusement, by means of pretty face, smart calls…”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref23&quot;&gt;[23]&lt;/a&gt; A reviewer in the  South China Morning Post, simply notes that it is a “bold thing” to put on the show in Hong Kong, and yet defends the show by saying that the jokes do “to some extent give one an idea of the Orientals” and that “if the local coloring is exaggerated, [they] would not have it otherwise.”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref24&quot;&gt;[24]&lt;/a&gt; Although this may be a reflection of dominant English-language use then, it is still strange to have a Hong Kong-based newspaper describe its own location as “Oriental”, a word that ultimately works to fetishize ones location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, besides the unrealistic names given to the Chinese characters of the show, it is worthy to note that the show does not include any Asian cast members, in both the original cast, the touring cast in Singapore and the touring cast in Hong Kong. Yellow-face may very well be used in the show, but this was never acknowledged in the newspapers, nor was the lack of Asian representation discussed. This perhaps points towards the popularity of the show among the Caucasian audiences in the colonies, both in Hong Kong and Singapore. The locations of the shows are also worthy a note, given that the Dallas Company staged the musical in prominent locations, such as the City Hall in Hong Kong.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref25&quot;&gt;[25]&lt;/a&gt; Given that the advertisement and reviews of the shows was found in English newspapers and the show itself was put on in English, it seemed likely that there would be a predominately English-speaking, and likely Caucasian, population in attendance. The largely positive reviews of a musical that ridicules what it means to be Chinese indicates the lack of Chinese and local perspectives both in the show and of the show. The musical theatre may hence be a more colonial, and likely privileged location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As seen from the newspaper archives of the show, the presence and voice of Chinese people were absent from the show, whether it be in the substantive content, the representation from the cast, crew and possibly the audience. The teleportation of the racially insensitive musical from a predominately upper-class Caucasian community to predominately Chinese societies has brought issues regarding race and class to the forefront of the discussion of what it means to be seen as the East. &lt;em&gt;Chinese Honeymoon&lt;/em&gt; reveals a particularly romanticized lens of what it means to be seen as Chinese by the West and the problematic notions this fetishization reveals in terms of racism, class and power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; A Chinese Honeymoon, a musical comedy in two acts, music by Howard Talbot, book and lyrics by George Dance, Chappell &amp;amp; Co. Ltd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ref2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; This approach is one referred to by Thomas Postlewait as one possible way of studying theatre historicity; Thomas Postlewait, The Cambridge Introduction to Theatre Historiography (Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 2012), 9–21.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; “A CHINESE HONEYMOON”, Era, 21 October 1899, https://link.gale.com/apps/doc/
BB3202531212/BNCN?u=hku&amp;amp;sid=BNCN&amp;amp;xid=7a68e87a.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt; THE PROMPTER. “‘P. I. P.’ PALYGOER,” Penny Illustrated Paper, 26 March 1904, 206, https://link.gale.com/apps/doc/BA3207741371/BNCN?u=hku&amp;amp;sid=BNCN&amp;amp;xid=37f95da6,.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref5&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ref5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/a&gt; Article 1 – No Title, South China Morning Post (1903-1941), 26 February 1904,
ProQuest Historical Newspapers: South China Morning Post, 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref6&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ref6&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/a&gt; “A CHINESE HONEYMOON”, Era, 21 October 1899. https://link.gale.com/apps/doc/
BB3202531212/BNCN?u=hku&amp;amp;sid=BNCN&amp;amp;xid=7a68e87a; Hong Kong Daily Press, 24 June 1904, NPDP19040624.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref7&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ref7&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/a&gt; THEATRE ROYAL: “A Chinese Honeymoon,” South China Morning Post (1903-1941), 24 February 1904, 5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref8&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ref8&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/a&gt; Ibid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref9&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ref9&quot;&gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/a&gt; “THE FOOTLIGHTS,” Northern Echo, 4 September 1900, https://link.gale.com/apps/
doc/BA3200280535/BNCN?u=hku&amp;amp;sid=BNCN&amp;amp;xid=cb36e745.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref10&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ref10&quot;&gt;[10]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/a&gt; “THE DALLAS COMPANY,” South China Morning Post (1903-1941), Feb 23, 1904, 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref12&quot;&gt;[12]&lt;/a&gt; Ibid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref13&quot;&gt;[13]&lt;/a&gt; “Article 6 – No Title”, South China Morning Post (1903-1941), 23 April 1904, 5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref14&quot;&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt; “A Chinese Honeymoon,” The Singapore Free Press and Mercantile Advertiser (Weekly), 15 June 1904, 374.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref15&quot;&gt;[15]&lt;/a&gt; “THE FOOTLIGHTS”, Northern Echo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref16&quot;&gt;[16]&lt;/a&gt; “A CHINESE HONEYMOON”, Era.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref17&quot;&gt;[17]&lt;/a&gt; “Synopsis,” Talbot, Dance, The Guide to Musical Theatre, http://www.guidetomusicaltheatre.com/shows_c/chinese_honeymoon.html.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref18&quot;&gt;[18]&lt;/a&gt; Anne Veronica Witchard, Thomas Burke’s dark chinoiserie: Limehouse nights and the queer spell of Chinatown (Farnham, Surrey: Ashgate Publishing, Ltd., 2009), 82.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref19&quot;&gt;[19]&lt;/a&gt; “THE FOOTLIGHTS”, Northern Echo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref20&quot;&gt;[20]&lt;/a&gt; Edward W. Said, Orientalism: Edward W. Said (New York: Vintage Books, 2003).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref21&quot;&gt;[21]&lt;/a&gt; Dongshin Chang, Representing China on the Historical London Stage: From Orientalism to Intercultural Performance (NYC/Abingdon-on-Thames: Routledge, 2015).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref22&quot;&gt;[22]&lt;/a&gt; Heidi J Holder, “Melodrama, Realism and Empire on the British Stage,” in Acts of Supremacy: The British Empire and the Stage, 1790-1930, ed. Bratton, 1991, 141-2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref23&quot;&gt;[23]&lt;/a&gt; “The War Between Japan and Russia,” Hong Kong Weekly Press 27 February 1904.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref24&quot;&gt;[24]&lt;/a&gt; “A Chinese Honeymoon,” The Singapore Free Press.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref26&quot;&gt;[25]&lt;/a&gt; “THE DALLAS COMPANY,” South China Morning Post (1903-1941).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref26&quot;&gt;[26]&lt;/a&gt; Ibid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;Bibliography&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“A CHINESE HONEYMOON.” &lt;em&gt;Era&lt;/em&gt;, 21 October 1899. British Library Newspapers, &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.gale.com/apps/doc/BB3202531212/BNCN?u=hku&amp;amp;sid=BNCN&amp;amp;xid=7a68e87a&quot;&gt;https://link.gale.com/apps/doc/BB3202531212/BNCN?u=hku&amp;amp;sid=BNCN&amp;amp;xid=7a68e87a.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“THE FOOTLIGHTS.” &lt;em&gt;Northern Echo&lt;/em&gt;, 4 September 1900. &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.gale.com/apps/doc/BA3200280535/BNCN?u=hku&amp;amp;sid=BNCN&amp;amp;xid=cb36e745&quot;&gt;https://link.gale.com/apps/doc/BA3200280535/BNCN?u=hku&amp;amp;sid=BNCN&amp;amp;xid=cb36e745&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“A Chinese Honeymoon.” &lt;em&gt;The Singapore Free Press and Mercantile Advertiser (Weekly)&lt;/em&gt;, 15 June 1904.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“Article 6 – No Title.” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 23 April 1904.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“Synopsis,” Talbot, Dance, &lt;em&gt;The Guide to Musical Theatre&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guidetomusicaltheatre.com/shows_c/chinese_honeymoon.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.guidetomusicaltheatre.com/shows_c/chinese_honeymoon.htm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“THE DALLAS COMPANY,” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 23 February 1904.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“The War Between Japan and Russia.” &lt;em&gt;Hong Kong Weekly Press&lt;/em&gt;, 27 February 1904.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Article 1 – No Title. &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 26 February 1904.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Chang, Dongshin. &lt;em&gt;Representing China on the Historical London Stage: From Orientalism to Intercultural Performance&lt;/em&gt;. NYC/Abingdon-on-Thames: Routledge, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Holder, Heidi J. “Melodrama, Realism and Empire on the British Stage.” In &lt;em&gt;Acts of Supremacy&lt;/em&gt;, edited by J.S. Bratton. Manchester: Manchester University Press, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hong Kong Daily Press,&lt;/em&gt; 24 June 1904. NPDP19040624.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Postlewait, Thomas. &lt;em&gt;The Cambridge Introduction to Theatre Historiography&lt;/em&gt;. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 2012, 9-21.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Said, Edward W. &lt;em&gt;Orientalism: Edward W. Said&lt;/em&gt;. New York: Vintage Books, 2003.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Talbot, Howard, George Dance. &lt;em&gt;A Chinese Honeymoon, a musical comedy in two acts&lt;/em&gt;. Hopwood &amp;amp; Crew, Limited, 1901.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;THE PROMPTER. “‘P. I. P.’ PALYGOER.” &lt;em&gt;Penny Illustrated Paper&lt;/em&gt;, 26 March 1904.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;THEATRE ROYAL: “A Chinese Honeymoon,” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 24 February 1904.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Witchard, Anne Veronica. &lt;em&gt;Thomas Burke’s dark chinoiserie: Limehouse nights and the queer spell of Chinatown&lt;/em&gt;. Farnham, Surrey: Ashgate Publishing, Ltd., 2009.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Theatre and Women’s Visibility in Nineteenth Century India</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/south%20asia/2020/08/14/khadija-azhar/"/>
   <updated>2020-08-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/south%20asia/2020/08/14/khadija-azhar</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Colonial subjugation forced a multitude of ideological changes in the Indian subcontinent—not many as hotly contested as the rights of Hindu women. Debates surrounding these rights surfaced repeatedly and invited deeply polarized opinions. While the British supported the advancement of the female condition as a natural step in India’s path to progress, orthodox Hindus criticized it as an attack on their cultural and religious autonomy. Amid this contention, theatre became a popular attraction for the native population as both a recreational and political space—one where these debates could be dissected under the guise of entertainment. With women’s rights occupying an important role in political discourse at the time, theatre helped transplant women’s experiences from the privacy of their homes and broadcast them publicly. This essay explores how theatre in the nineteenth century subcontinent allowed safe passage for women’s experiences to proliferate public spaces&lt;a href=&quot;#ref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; but argues that this visibility was undermined by mechanisms that divested them of control over these narratives. Hindu women’s relationship with the public sphere will first be contextualized, followed by a discussion on how theatre helped them access it. This will then be contested based on women’s inability to control the projection of their narratives, and to question the ones imposed onto them on stage. Tanika Sarkar’s book &lt;em&gt;Hindu Wife, Hindu Nation: Community, Religion, and Cultural Nationalism&lt;/em&gt;, will be used to supplement the essay, in tandem with archival sources that document the workings of theatre in nineteenth century India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hindu women had a complicated relationship with public space, characterized largely by their devotion to chastity and domesticity. The traditional upper-caste Hindu woman was married as a child and expected to cohabit with her husband as soon as she attained puberty.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; If her husband died, she was either burnt on the pyre or was not allowed to remarry.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; Following her marriage, she was placed into a life of seclusion that kept her away from all modes of institutional education.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt; Restricted from the public in forced conjugality, women turned to a life of domesticity and the &lt;em&gt;zenana&lt;/em&gt;—the private space within the home—became their domain&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Hindu nationalists justified infant marriages by positing that, “… a lifetime of togetherness beginning with infancy guaranteed a superior … compatibility” and “… was also kinder to women since it ensured … a hold on the husband’s affection [and] an integration with the family.”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt; This compatibility was emphasized as a lifelong commitment, one that would continue even if the husband died. The &lt;em&gt;zenana&lt;/em&gt;, on the other hand, was “not a dungeon as it was represented by some” but “a place of social union and purity” in the nationalist mind.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref6&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt; Consequently, chastity and domesticity became underlying requirements for a society that framed infant marriages and restrictions on widow remarriage as a labour of love and excluded many Hindu women from the public space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the adoption of theatre into native circles, many Indian women were allowed newfound access to public sphere.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref7&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt; They began appearing on stage as professional actors, a development initially championed in 1859 by writer Madhusudan Dutt of the Bengali theatre.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref8&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt; In fact, actors of the time such as Binodini Dasi and Tara Sundari received much acclaim for their abilities, with Sundari paralleled to the likes of Sarah Bernhardt.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref9&quot;&gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt; While most of these women were originally sex workers, the stage also attracted “women abandoned by husbands or lovers, or widows” who were looking largely for employment. Moreover, women began appearing in theatre audiences when the Bengali theatre began attempts to reframe the art form as “family entertainment” by designating viewing spaces for women.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref10&quot;&gt;[10]&lt;/a&gt; As a result, it not only became a source of economic empowerment, but seemed to provide a mediated public space where women of multiple backgrounds and hierarchies were able to shed the restrictions of a private life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arguably the most important development in theatrical tradition was the focus on domestic spheres. Women’s lives had largely been restricted to the &lt;em&gt;zenana&lt;/em&gt; before theatre gave them a place to appear in public, and their narratives began to proliferate into public consciousness. At times, these narratives revolved around the injustices experienced by women, allowing potential for greater progressive discourse. For example, in 1873, Bengal’s first native pantomime shed some light on “the sorrows of the Hindu widow” in an impassioned speech, addressing the controversies regarding widow remarriage:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How absurd … of the English to abolish widow burning, which at least afforded a speedy end to a life of misery, since they did not at the same time abolish the law against the remarriage of widows.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref11&quot;&gt;[11]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although women were not given physical representation in the play (all actors were men, with women’s parts assigned to boys), it amplified Hindu women’s voices and shed light on their grievances. This visibility was further compounded in the performance reviews published in newspapers, extending the audience of the play to people who were not physically in attendance. Consequently, Western theatre seemed to offer more opportunities for empowerment to the Hindu woman by providing a public space where her narrative could be explored freely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, delving deeper into the role of theatre in women’s empowerment reveals impositions that weakened their visibility. It may be argued that in the realm of theatre, the actor is merely a vessel; she accepts the narratives imposed upon her by the audience, and the plot, without being able to project her own. Expounding upon the former, theatre in the nineteenth century was frequented largely by the predominantly male ruling class, who condemned public appearance as the ultimate transgression for Hindu women.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref12&quot;&gt;[12]&lt;/a&gt; They believed that these actors were “fallen women”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref13&quot;&gt;[13]&lt;/a&gt; and anxiety prevailed that they posed a threat to the purity of young male actors,&lt;a href=&quot;#ref14&quot;&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt; echoing the sentiments that used to dictate perceptions of &lt;em&gt;nautch&lt;/em&gt; girls.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref15&quot;&gt;[15]&lt;/a&gt; With no way for them to contest this imposition, women’s access to public spaces continued to validate patriarchal associations between visibility and shame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the audience, the drama itself eclipsed the actor’s personhood. Even though women were allowed to act, they possessed no control over what they portrayed on stage and so, their personal narratives remained outside of public view. At times, this resulted in women endorsing the same patriarchal views that kept them disenfranchised. Perhaps the best example of this stark incongruency would be a play staged by famous Marathi writer, Krushnaji Prabhakar Khadilkar in 1907, titled &lt;em&gt;A Women’s Revolt&lt;/em&gt;. This play was “performed by a company composed so largely of women that “not only all the heroines but some of the heroes also were represented by members of the fairer sex,”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref16&quot;&gt;[16]&lt;/a&gt; reversing the longstanding tradition of boys performing the roles of women. At the outset, it seemed to be providing women with unprecedented visibility in the theatrical space. However, analyzing the plot reveals exactly the disparities that this essay attempts to delineate. Using Tennyson’s “Princess” as the basis of his drama, Khadilkar wrote a gripping epic on imperial India.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref17&quot;&gt;[17]&lt;/a&gt; The plot centers around an all-female kingdom that bars men from even stepping foot inside its boundaries. Its illusory independence falls apart when the Princess agrees to enter a “marriage of equality”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref18&quot;&gt;[18]&lt;/a&gt; with a man, restoring the family and domesticity as sacrosanct institutions for the women of the kingdom. The disintegration of this kingdom followed by the restoration of peace embodies an inherent conflict between women’s independence and conjugality. Early twentieth-century India was rife with debates on women’s remarriage, infant marriage and women’s education—all of which grappled with cultural and religious restrictions on female autonomy. With playwrights as influential as Khadilkar broadcasting their independence as a disruption in the natural order, women’s appearance on this stage ended up validating doctrines that supported restrictions on their visibility. As a result, these women became as helpless in subverting the dominant patriarchal narrative as those restricted to the &lt;em&gt;zenana&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref19&quot;&gt;[19]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, there were times when theatre aimed a spotlight at the injustices that plagued women’s lives but framed them in ways that were inherently patriarchal. While such performances did not necessarily involve female actors, they seemed to bring women’s narratives into the open, but manipulated them to conform to public perceptions. For example, in 1873, the Guru of a wealthy Saivite temple was accused of seducing a young girl named Elokeshi and then raping her.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref20&quot;&gt;[20]&lt;/a&gt; Her husband initially forgave her for what he believed was her transgression, but when accosted by the Guru’s men, he slit Elokeshi’s throat in a fit of rage. Sarkar explains the theatrical adoption of this story:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theatre at the time provided more publicity to this event than would have been given initially. Certainly, the largest corpus among nineteenth century farces related to a single contemporary event.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref21&quot;&gt;[21]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the outset, this visibility seems unprecedented, but it is to be noted that these performances were largely farces that did little to evoke public sympathy for Elokeshi. Many focused on the punishment and humiliation faced by the Guru, while some showed him as a repentant figure, decentring the narrative from Elokeshi’s death.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref22&quot;&gt;[22]&lt;/a&gt; In addition, unable to deny the facts of the rape and murder, some framed her stepmother as the culprit who forced her husband to sell Elokeshi to the Guru for material gain.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref23&quot;&gt;[23]&lt;/a&gt; Not only did this help reconcile the incident with “a more familiar … register of misogyny,” but also helped justify people’s fears of “a wife’s prolonged sojourn at her natal home.”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref24&quot;&gt;[24]&lt;/a&gt; As a result, an incident that reflected one of the gravest injustices perpetrated against women was manipulated to validate the stigma associated with her actions, or the actions of the women around her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Historical accounts where women have been able to voice their own experiences dismantle the illusion that their commitment to chastity and domesticity was a labour of love, as Hindu nationalists would frame. In fact, their accounts painted an entirely different picture. One of the most celebrated actors of the time, Binodini Dasi, wrote an autobiography which she prefaced with a summary of her misfortune:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There is no one in this world before whom I can lay bare my pain, for the world sees me as a sinner—a fallen woman … I am a social outcast—a despicable prostitute. Why should people feel compassion for me?&lt;a href=&quot;#ref25&quot;&gt;[25]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the orthodox Hindu perspectives, the misery she endured was justified given her previous profession, and her acclaim as an actor was secondary. Despite the visibility that theatre provided, her suffering echoes that of the women who spent their lives in seclusion. As Sarkar notes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[Women] wrote about the trauma … of infant marriage, the deprivations of the widow, the absence of love in the lives of wives … All varieties of women’s writings unanimously identified and condemned two problem spots within the Hindu woman’s existence—the pain of patrilocality and the longing for knowledge.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref26&quot;&gt;[26]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The unanimity of the suffering expressed across multiple accounts penned by women in the nineteenth century confirms that the theatrical proliferation of their narratives was inauthentic, to say the least. At times, theatre ended up bolstering patriarchal impositions while rendering female actors’ complicit in these endorsements. As a result, the visibility it seemed to provide to women and their narratives became illusory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theatre in the nineteenth century subcontinent may have reconfigured women’s relationship with the public sphere, insofar as they were allowed to step out of the private domain. However, this loosening of physical constraints did not translate into an ideological emancipation; women were still judged within the same patriarchal frameworks that forced their seclusion. Most importantly, they could not subvert these ideas due to the limits placed on their agency by the theatre. In conclusion, theatre contributed to the exclusion of women’s narratives from public discourse by refusing them control over how they were viewed and could inadvertently have helped perpetuate the restrictions that women’s visibility could potentially have countered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; This essay does not seek to extrapolate its conclusions to all women in nineteenth century India but attempts to illuminate some of the patriarchal impositions that complicated their lives, using the dominant religious and cultural doctrines of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; Tanika Sarkar, Hindu Wife, Hindu Nation: Community, Religion, and Cultural Nationalism (Bloomington, IN: Indiana University Press, 2001), 124.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; Ibid, 41.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt; “Editorial Article 1 – no Title,” The Times of India (1861-Current), 16 June 1885, http://eproxy.lib.hku.hk/login?url=https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/234457615?accountid=14548.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt; Sarkar, 40.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref6&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt; THE IMPROVEMENT OF WOMEN,” The Times of India (1861-Current), 18 December 1877, http://eproxy.lib.hku.hk/login?url=https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/234648113?accountid=14548.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref7&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt; It would be inaccurate to claim that women were not afforded any visibility before the import of Western theatre. In the nineteenth century, the nautch as a cultural form seemed to provide some women a similar window into the public domain where they were seen on stage, under the proverbial spotlight. However, the visibility it provided was not only restricted to a certain caste, but also came with its own patriarchal impositions. The nautch girls’ presence in public was framed as evidence of their misfortune, and associations between immorality and the nautch were solidified; it became a stage only for lower-caste women. Moreover, the nautch may have been as restricting as the zenana in women’s ability to control how people viewed them, as it existed purely for the male gaze and did not provide room for individual expression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref8&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt; Rimli Bhattacharya, “Introduction: Binodini Dasi and the Public Theatre in Nineteenth century Bengal,” in My Story and My Life as an Actress, trans. Rimli Bhattacharya (New Delhi: Kali for Women, 1998), 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref9&quot;&gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt; “DRAMA OF BENGAL,” The Times of India (1861-Current), 22 July 1931, http://eproxy.lib.hku.hk/login?url=https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/325237325?accountid=14548.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref10&quot;&gt;[10]&lt;/a&gt; Sarkar, 89.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref11&quot;&gt;[11]&lt;/a&gt; “Theatre in Bengal,” The Times of India (1861-Current), 17 February 1873.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref12&quot;&gt;[12]&lt;/a&gt; Bhattacharya, 6.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref13&quot;&gt;[13]&lt;/a&gt; Ibid, 26.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref14&quot;&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt; Anu Bandyopadhyaya, “Look Back with Pride.” The Times of India (1861-Current), 17 December 1972, http://eproxy.lib.hku.hk/login?url=https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/614022799?accountid=14548.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref15&quot;&gt;[15]&lt;/a&gt; Winter’s Tale, “Literature: THE DANCING GIRL,” The Bombay Times and Journal of Commerce (1838-1859), 19 April 1845, http://eproxy.lib.hku.hk/login?url=https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/233707662?accountid=14548.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref16&quot;&gt;[16]&lt;/a&gt; C, N. K., “A MARATHI COMEDY: A WOMEN’S REVOLT,” The Times of India (1861-Current), 15 May 1908, http://eproxy.lib.hku.hk/login?url=https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/231329994?accountid=14548.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref17&quot;&gt;[17]&lt;/a&gt; Ibid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref18&quot;&gt;[18]&lt;/a&gt; Ibid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref19&quot;&gt;[19]&lt;/a&gt; Rashsundari, an upper-caste woman who wrote the first autobiography written in Bengali in 1876, echoes these ideas by describing herself as an actor who is “blindly manipulated” (Sarkar, 113) in a play “scripted and the directed” by God (Sarkar, 113). Just like Rashsundari in the domestic domain, the actors on stage were unable to contest the narratives imposed upon them by men, despite their apparent agency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref20&quot;&gt;[20]&lt;/a&gt; Sarkar, 57.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref21&quot;&gt;[21]&lt;/a&gt; Ibid, 60.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref22&quot;&gt;[22]&lt;/a&gt; Ibid, 79.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref23&quot;&gt;[23]&lt;/a&gt; Ibid, 85.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref24&quot;&gt;[24]&lt;/a&gt; Ibid, 86.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref25&quot;&gt;[25]&lt;/a&gt; Dasi, 49.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref26&quot;&gt;[26]&lt;/a&gt; Sarkar, 45.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;Bibliography&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Bandyopadhyaya, Anu. “Look Back with Pride.” &lt;em&gt;The Times of India (1861-Current),&lt;/em&gt; 17 December 1972. &lt;a href=&quot;http://eproxy.lib.hku.hk/login?url=https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/614022799?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;http://eproxy.lib.hku.hk/login?url=https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/614022799?accountid=14548.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Bhattacharya, Rimli. “Introduction: Binodini Dasi and the Public Theatre in Nineteenth century Bengal.” In &lt;em&gt;My Story and My Life as an Actress&lt;/em&gt;, translated by Rimli Bhattacharya. New Delhi: Kali for Women, 1998.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;C, N. K. “A MARATHI COMEDY: A WOMEN’S REVOLT.” &lt;em&gt;The Times of India (1861-Current),&lt;/em&gt; 15 May 1908. &lt;a href=&quot;http://eproxy.lib.hku.hk/login?url=https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/231329994?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;http://eproxy.lib.hku.hk/login?url=https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/231329994?accountid=14548.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“DRAMA OF BENGAL.” &lt;em&gt;The Times of India (1861-Current),&lt;/em&gt; 22 July 1931. &lt;a href=&quot;http://eproxy.lib.hku.hk/login?url=https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/325237325?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;http://eproxy.lib.hku.hk/login?url=https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/325237325?accountid=14548.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“THE IMPROVEMENT OF WOMEN.” &lt;em&gt;The Times of India (1861-Current),&lt;/em&gt; 18 December 1877. &lt;a href=&quot;http://eproxy.lib.hku.hk/login?url=https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/234648113?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;http://eproxy.lib.hku.hk/login?url=https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/234648113?accountid=14548&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“Editorial Article 1 – no Title.” &lt;em&gt;The Times of India (1861-Current),&lt;/em&gt; 26 June 1885. &lt;a href=&quot;http://eproxy.lib.hku.hk/login?url=https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/234457615?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;http://eproxy.lib.hku.hk/login?url=https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/234457615?accountid=14548.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“THE THEATRE IN BENGAL.” &lt;em&gt;The Times of India (1861-Current),&lt;/em&gt; 17 February 1873.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Winter’s Tale. “Literature: THE DANCING GIRL.” &lt;em&gt;The Bombay Times and Journal of Commerce (1838-1859),&lt;/em&gt; Apr 19, 1845. http://eproxy.lib.hku.hk/login?url=https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/docview/233707662?accountid=14548.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The significance of theatre and charity in Hong Kong from the early to mid-20th Century</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/hong%20kong/2020/08/14/jasper-kwok/"/>
   <updated>2020-08-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/hong%20kong/2020/08/14/jasper-kwok</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Theatre is a performing art form that has been used to entertain audiences all around the world for many generations. However, stage productions are often organised to fulfill even greater, deeper purposes beyond simply being used to amuse the members of any given society. In the first half of the 20th century, specifically in 1937, the Second Sino-Japanese War erupted between the Republic of China and the Empire of Japan. As a result of this severe outbreak of conflict, thousands of mainland Chinese refugees were forced to flee to Hong Kong for a safe haven to escape the advancing Japanese forces.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; As such, during this time various Chinese theatrical productions took place in Hong Kong aimed at raising and donating the proceeding funds to war charities to support wounded Chinese soldiers, victims and refugees. This essay will delve into the historical and socio-economic significance of theatre and charity in Hong Kong from the early to mid-20th Century; I will explore how Chinese theatrical performances were primarily organised to generate funds for various charities. Subsequently, I will show how they reflected the sociological and economic conditions at the time by raising awareness on the issues and tribulations faced by China as a whole. The use of the term “charity” in this essay refers to the “voluntary giving of help” to those who are less fortunate and in need, usually through the raising and donation of money.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The role and nature of the theatrical performances that were organised during the early and mid-20th century were primarily meant to benefit deserving charitable causes, to reflect the times and the social and economic state that Hong Kong was in when they were presented to the public, as well as to promote a level of patriotism and love for one’s own country. For example, the Chinese Women’s New Life Movement organised a four hour play entitled &lt;em&gt;My Country First and Last&lt;/em&gt; at the Tai Ping Theatre in 1940, for which the entirety of the receipts were devoted to causes like the War Charities Fund, which aided injured Chinese soldiers on the front lines as well as fleeing refugees. In addition, this play was notably a romance story set during a war between Nan Shang and Tung Hoi, establishing clear parallels with the Sino-Japanese War raging at the time of its release.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; Such charity-driven plays were generally successful and well supported by the public as they typically yielded a substantial amount of income and proceeds.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt; The total amount of funds collected by theatrical productions would also be detailed extensively in newspapers to let members of the public know how their vast proceeds will help in furthering deserving causes.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt; This is of notable significance as newspapers and theatrical companies wanted audience members who contributed to know how crucial they were in benefiting the community, thus promoting a sense of patriotism and pride among members of Hong Kong society. In this way, the act of “giving to charities” offstage can also be perceived as a form of “double performance” put on by the media and theatrical companies; by informing the audience of their significance in benefitting their country, theatre groups hoped that members of the public were positively impacted by this experience and would subsequently be further inclined to attend other charity-related plays again in the future to attain a similar sense of self-gratification and worth. Therefore, theatrical companies responsible for on stage performances benefited from the act of charity and “double performance” put on for the public, and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be said that all of these underlying motives and factors are endogenous factors, as detailed in the first crux of theatre historiography by Thomas Postlewait, initiated by the agents that were responsible for the organisation of these theatrical productions, who clearly had an aim, a vision and a message that they wanted to promote in Hong Kong society. The war setting of these plays, in particular, can also be related to crux three, in which the cultural and symbolic codes of communication present in Hong Kong during the early to mid-20th century may have played a large part in the positive impact of these theatrical performances.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref6&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another important purpose of Chinese theatrical productions at the time was to promote patriotism and love for China as a country even &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; the war had ended among audience members. Numerous stage plays were held to sponsor the erection of a Chinese War Memorial Hall to honor those who lost their lives during the Sino-Japanese War.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref7&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt; This was a means of getting the public to appreciate the sacrifices made by thousands of servicemen and soldiers who gave their lives defending their country, and to remember the innocent civilians who paid the ultimate price in times of war.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that many plays seeking to raise money for causes like the War Charities Fund were performed at a major theatre in the Tai Ping district, which served as Hong Kong’s central business district, highlights that Chinese theatrical performances at the time were intended to draw as large an audience as possible.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref8&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt; According to the &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post&lt;/em&gt;, the record sum raised for war charities by a singular theatrical performance organised by the Pat Wo Dramatic Association held in the Tai Ping district, which was attended by His Excellency the Governor and Lady Northcote, was $7,025.10. These funds were also donated to the British War Organisation Fund.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref9&quot;&gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt; The moral role of such theatrical plays may thus have been to educate its audience and get them to be aware of the hardships and toil faced by Chinese soldiers at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 1940 plays &lt;em&gt;Life is But a Dream&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Woman and Wit&lt;/em&gt; were also held at the Tai Ping Theatre and ultimately collectively raised up to $20,000 to aid the British War Organisation Fund.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref10&quot;&gt;[10]&lt;/a&gt; Since Hong Kong was owned by Britain at the time, naturally some plays were made exclusively to entertain the British force, and the funds raised by such theatrical performances would be given to several British causes as well. The Tai Ping District is also notable for being where many British people resided, showing that these plays also sought to appeal to and attract as eclectic a range of ethnic and racial groups as possible in Hong Kong’s central business district by catering to both locals and the British. The gestures, clothes, mannerisms, conventions, traditions, and practices featured in such plays were accurately reflective of Chinese and Hong Kong culture at the time. And these productions featured English translators and interpreters to make it easier for foreigners to understand and learn from them. Therefore, in addition to providing “pleasant entertainment” and promoting patriotism among locals, the artists responsible for creating such performances clearly sought to educate foreigners as well whilst simultaneously helping various worthy causes by donating large sums to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it should be noted that far from all Chinese theatrical performances at the time were solely dedicated to raising money and awareness for war-related charities, as several theatrical performances were held to raise money for other worthy causes as well. For instance, several other stage plays were put on to celebrate Chinese religion and give British individuals a taste of what Chinese culture and traditions were like at the time. In 1927, plays were put on that celebrated the anniversary of the Republic of China.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref11&quot;&gt;[11]&lt;/a&gt; In 1946, three consecutive performances were given that celebrated Taoism and wished the audience “a long life”. The final performance produced by the Chinese Entertainment Organisation was set during the Sung Dynasty, a century old time period, and featured authentic costumes reflective of the ones worn so long ago, thereby immersing the British Forces in China’s history and allowing them to witness a “real Chinese stage performance”. Special tram services were even put in place to make reaching the Ko Shing Theatre easier for audience members.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref12&quot;&gt;[12]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another example of non-war-related performances were the plays held by the Wanchai Kaifong Welfare Association in the 1940s and 50s, the proceeds of which were devoted to aiding numerous social welfare issues in Hong Kong. This included an unfortunate lack of access to education, health and clothing by the poorer classes of society.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref13&quot;&gt;[13]&lt;/a&gt; The proceeds of such performances were thus dedicated to the construction of free schools, health clinics, shelters, and even fully-fledged hospitals for the poorer members of the public, in addition to raising funds for relief work.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref14&quot;&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt; Disabled and less fortunate children were a particularly common charitable cause that theatrical productions sought to raise funds for.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref15&quot;&gt;[15]&lt;/a&gt; Governors or other individuals in positions of power attended performances at the Ko Shing Theatre and wrote cheques to raise money for aerated waters for the less fortunate.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref16&quot;&gt;[16]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be said that the causes theatrical performances in Hong Kong benefited also depended on the social, economic or environmental condition of China at a certain point in time. For example, the city of Swatow was rocked by a devastating typhoon from July to August in 1922. The Swatow Typhoon is established as “one of the worst typhoons” that ever passed over the Far East with a wind velocity of “over 100 miles per hour”. The typhoon caused a tidal wave that rose 12 feet above high water” and claimed more than 100,000 lives in the Swatow area.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref17&quot;&gt;[17]&lt;/a&gt; In response to this tragedy and natural disaster, Hong Kong university students put a play together to aid those who were affected by the natural disaster.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref18&quot;&gt;[18]&lt;/a&gt; This relates to the second crux of Thomas Postlewait, “the encompassing or exogenous conditions that directly or indirectly contributed to the event’s manifest identity and intelligibility”. Exogenous factors that affect a theatrical performance refers to the external social and environmental conditions of the time and place during which a play was created and presented.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref19&quot;&gt;[19]&lt;/a&gt; Hong Kong and China’s exogenous factors therefore significantly contributed to the rise of theatrical performances in Hong Kong as the century progressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, theatre has been used to entertain audiences all around the world for many generations. However, stage productions are also organised to fulfill greater purposes of socio-economic significance beyond simply amusing members of society. Chinese theatrical productions that took place in Hong Kong from the early to mid-20th century primarily aimed at raising and donating the proceeding funds to war charities to support those wounded during the severe war raging at the time. But in addition to being organised to generate funds for various charities, Chinese theatrical performances also served to reflect the sociological and economic conditions at the time, as well as to raise awareness for the issues and tribulations faced by China as a country as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; “Hong Kong Profile – Timeline,” &lt;em&gt;BBC&lt;/em&gt;, 24 June 2019, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-pacific-16526765&quot;&gt;www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-pacific-16526765&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; Lexico Dictionaries, “Charity: Definition of Charity by Lexico,” &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lexico.com/en/definition/charity&quot;&gt;www.lexico.com/en/definition/charity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; “RELIEF FUND DRIVE: Theatrical Performances At Tai Ping To-Night,” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 4 January 1940, 12, &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1760120428/A1AAF42B4CA24249PQ/5?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1760120428/A1AAF42B4CA24249PQ/5?accountid=14548&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt; Chu Pak Lau, “CHINESE THEATRICAL PERFORMANCES: $19,600 FOR WAR CHARITIES FUND,” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 21 December 1916, 3, &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1499970100/A1AAF42B4CA24249PQ/4?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1499970100/A1AAF42B4CA24249PQ/4?accountid=14548&lt;/a&gt;; Mei Lan-Fan, “CHARITY SHOWS: Recent Performances,” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 22 June 1931, 9, &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1757316426/9565F78882244E0FPQ/15?accountid=1454&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1757316426/9565F78882244E0FPQ/15?accountid=1454&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt; Ip Kwai-Chung. “CORRESPONDENCE: Proceeds of Theatricals (To the Editor. S. C. M. Post.),” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;(1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 27 December 1932, 11, &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1757380348/606B0DBEFBB84088PQ/20?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1757380348/606B0DBEFBB84088PQ/20?accountid=14548&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref6&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt; Thomas Postlewait, &lt;em&gt;The Cambridge Introduction to Theatre Historiography&lt;/em&gt; (New York: Cambridge University Press, 2009), 225-40.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref7&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt; “WAR MEMORIAL HALL: Theatrical Performances To Raise Funds.” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 7 January 1947, 2, &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1535769202/A1AAF42B4CA24249PQ/8?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1535769202/A1AAF42B4CA24249PQ/8?accountid=14548&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref8&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt; Chu Pak Lau, “CHINESE THEATRICAL PERFORMANCES: $19,600 FOR WAR CHARITIES FUND,” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;(1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 21 December 1916, 3, &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1499970100/A1AAF42B4CA24249PQ/4?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1499970100/A1AAF42B4CA24249PQ/4?accountid=14548&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref9&quot;&gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt; “RECORD SUM RAISED.” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 3 February 1940, 2, &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1760132241/87FCCCF3828D43AEPQ/8?accountid=1454&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1760132241/87FCCCF3828D43AEPQ/8?accountid=1454&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref10&quot;&gt;[10]&lt;/a&gt; Variety Entertainment, “CHINESE THEATRICAL SHOW AIDS B.W.O.F: Large Sum Expected From Tai Ping Performances,” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 17 January 1940, 1, &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1760126135/606B0DBEFBB84088PQ/14?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1760126135/606B0DBEFBB84088PQ/14?accountid=14548&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref11&quot;&gt;[11]&lt;/a&gt; “THE DOUBLE TENTH: Police Reserve Theatrical Performance GOVERNOR ATTENDS,” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941),&lt;/em&gt; 12 October 1927, 3, &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1500238258/A1AAF42B4CA24249PQ/10?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1500238258/A1AAF42B4CA24249PQ/10?accountid=14548&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref12&quot;&gt;[12]&lt;/a&gt; W.K. Tong, “CHINESE PLAYS: Theatrical Performance At Ko Shing PROGRAMME SUMMARY,” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941),&lt;/em&gt; 8 January 1946, 3, &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1535700201/9565F78882244E0FPQ/10?accountid=1454&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1535700201/9565F78882244E0FPQ/10?accountid=1454&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref13&quot;&gt;[13]&lt;/a&gt; “Theatrical Performances.” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941),&lt;/em&gt; 8 November 1958, 7, &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1532253441/A1AAF42B4CA24249PQ/1?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1532253441/A1AAF42B4CA24249PQ/1?accountid=14548&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref14&quot;&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt; “CHINESE OPERA: Governor Attends Charity Performance IN AID OF SPC,” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941),&lt;/em&gt; 18 July 1948, 4, &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1766445970/87FCCCF3828D43AEPQ/11?accountid=1454&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1766445970/87FCCCF3828D43AEPQ/11?accountid=1454&lt;/a&gt;; “BIG SUM RAISED: Charity Balls and Theatre Performances Profit,” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941),&lt;/em&gt; 5 May 1939, 10, &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1760406077/87FCCCF3828D43AEPQ/9?accountid=1454&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1760406077/87FCCCF3828D43AEPQ/9?accountid=1454&lt;/a&gt;; I.P. Kwai-Chung, “Recent Charity Theatricals,” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941),&lt;/em&gt; 26 July 1933, 11, &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1757459750/606B0DBEFBB84088PQ/15?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1757459750/606B0DBEFBB84088PQ/15?accountid=14548&lt;/a&gt;; “AMBULANCE WORK: Theatrical Performances at Ko Shing Theatre.” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941),&lt;/em&gt; 17 July 1933, 11, &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1757452651/606B0DBEFBB84088PQ/7?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1757452651/606B0DBEFBB84088PQ/7?accountid=14548&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref15&quot;&gt;[15]&lt;/a&gt; “Endeavourers School Plan,” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941),&lt;/em&gt; 20 May 1959, 6, &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1532348507/87FCCCF3828D43AEPQ/7?accountid=1454&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1532348507/87FCCCF3828D43AEPQ/7?accountid=1454&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref16&quot;&gt;[16]&lt;/a&gt; “IN AID OF CHARITY: Special Performances at Ko Shing Theatre GOVERNOR SENDS CHEQUE,” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941),&lt;/em&gt; 15 July 1931, 15, &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1538776629/9565F78882244E0FPQ/16?accountid=1454&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1538776629/9565F78882244E0FPQ/16?accountid=1454&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref17&quot;&gt;[17]&lt;/a&gt; Pedro Ribera, Ricardo García-Herrera, Luis Gimeno, and Emiliano Hernández, “The Selga Chronology, Part II: 1901-1934,” &lt;em&gt;Risk Prediction Initiative&lt;/em&gt;, Universidad Complutense de Madrid, &lt;a href=&quot;http://webs.ucm.es/info/tropical/selga-ii.html&quot;&gt;webs.ucm.es/info/tropical/selga-ii.html.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref18&quot;&gt;[18]&lt;/a&gt; “SWATOW RELIEF: A THEATRICAL PERFORMANCE,” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941),&lt;/em&gt; 29 August 1922, 7, &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1499574518/606B0DBEFBB84088PQ/2?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1499574518/606B0DBEFBB84088PQ/2?accountid=14548&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref19&quot;&gt;[19]&lt;/a&gt; Postlewait, 233-6.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;Bibliography&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“AMBULANCE WORK: Theatrical Performances at Ko Shing Theatre.” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941),&lt;/em&gt; 17 July 1933. &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1757452651/606B0DBEFBB84088PQ/7?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1757452651/606B0DBEFBB84088PQ/7?accountid=14548&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“BIG SUM RAISED: Charity Balls and Theatre Performances Profit.” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941),&lt;/em&gt; 5 May 1939. &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1760406077/87FCCCF3828D43AEPQ/9?accountid=1454&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1760406077/87FCCCF3828D43AEPQ/9?accountid=1454&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“CHINESE OPERA: Governor Attends Charity Performance IN AID OF SPC.” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941),&lt;/em&gt; 18 July 1948. &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1766445970/87FCCCF3828D43AEPQ/11?accountid=1454&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1766445970/87FCCCF3828D43AEPQ/11?accountid=1454&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“CHINESE THEATRICAL PERFORMANCES: FOB WAR CHARITIES FUND.” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941),&lt;/em&gt; 7 December 1916. &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1499968998/A1AAF42B4CA24249PQ/6?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1499968998/A1AAF42B4CA24249PQ/6?accountid=14548&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“Endeavourers School Plan.” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941),&lt;/em&gt; 20 May 1959. &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1532348507/87FCCCF3828D43AEPQ/7?accountid=1454&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1532348507/87FCCCF3828D43AEPQ/7?accountid=1454&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“Hong Kong Profile - Timeline.” &lt;em&gt;BBC&lt;/em&gt;, 24 June 2019. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-pacific-16526765&quot;&gt;www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-pacific-16526765&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“IN AID OF CHARITY: Special Performances at Ko Shing Theatre GOVERNOR SENDS CHEQUE.” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941),&lt;/em&gt; 15 July 1931. &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1538776629/9565F78882244E0FPQ/16?accountid=1454&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1538776629/9565F78882244E0FPQ/16?accountid=1454&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“RECORD SUM RAISED.” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 3 February 1940. &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1760132241/87FCCCF3828D43AEPQ/8?accountid=1454&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1760132241/87FCCCF3828D43AEPQ/8?accountid=1454&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“RELIEF FUND DRIVE: Theatrical Performances At Tai Ping To-Night.” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941),&lt;/em&gt; 4 January 1940. &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1760120428/A1AAF42B4CA24249PQ/5?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1760120428/A1AAF42B4CA24249PQ/5?accountid=14548&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“SWATOW RELIEF: A THEATRICAL PERFORMANCE.” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941),&lt;/em&gt; 29 August 1922. &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1499574518/606B0DBEFBB84088PQ/2?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1499574518/606B0DBEFBB84088PQ/2?accountid=14548&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“THE DOUBLE TENTH: Police Reserve Theatrical Performance GOVERNOR ATTENDS.” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941),&lt;/em&gt; 12 October 1927. &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1500238258/A1AAF42B4CA24249PQ/10?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1500238258/A1AAF42B4CA24249PQ/10?accountid=14548&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“Theatrical Performances.” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941),&lt;/em&gt; 8 November 1958. &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1532253441/A1AAF42B4CA24249PQ/1?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1532253441/A1AAF42B4CA24249PQ/1?accountid=14548&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“WAR MEMORIAL HALL: Theatrical Performances To Raise Funds.” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941),&lt;/em&gt; 7 January 1947. &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1535769202/A1AAF42B4CA24249PQ/8?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1535769202/A1AAF42B4CA24249PQ/8?accountid=14548&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Doggett, Jill. “Performance by the Royal Ballet: A Great Treat for Lovers of Art in Hongkong Gala Charity Premiere to Be Held next Month.” &lt;em&gt;South China Sunday Post&lt;/em&gt;, 30 April 1961. &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1533316881/87FCCCF3828D43AEPQ/14?accountid=1454&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1533316881/87FCCCF3828D43AEPQ/14?accountid=1454&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Kwai-Chung, I.P. “Recent Charity Theatricals.” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941),&lt;/em&gt; 26 July 1933. &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1757459750/606B0DBEFBB84088PQ/15?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1757459750/606B0DBEFBB84088PQ/15?accountid=14548&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Kwai-Chung, IP. “CORRESPONDENCE: Proceeds of Theatricals (To the Editor. S. C. M. Post.).” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941),&lt;/em&gt; 27 December 1932. &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1757380348/606B0DBEFBB84088PQ/20?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1757380348/606B0DBEFBB84088PQ/20?accountid=14548&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Lan-Fan, Mei. “CHARITY SHOWS: Recent Performances.” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941),&lt;/em&gt; 22 June 1931. &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1757316426/9565F78882244E0FPQ/15?accountid=1454&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1757316426/9565F78882244E0FPQ/15?accountid=1454&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Lau, Chu Pak. “CHINESE THEATRICAL PERFORMANCES: $19,600 FOR WAR CHARITIES FUND.” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941),&lt;/em&gt; 21 December 1916. &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1499970100/A1AAF42B4CA24249PQ/4?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1499970100/A1AAF42B4CA24249PQ/4?accountid=14548&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Lexico Dictionaries. “Charity: Definition of Charity by Lexico.” &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lexico.com/en/definition/charity&quot;&gt;www.lexico.com/en/definition/charity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Postlewait, Thomas. &lt;em&gt;The Cambridge Introduction to Theatre Historiography&lt;/em&gt;. New York: Cambridge University Press, 2009.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Ribera, Pedro, Ricardo García-Herrera, Luis Gimeno, and Emiliano Hernández. “The Selga Chronology, Part II: 1901-1934.” &lt;em&gt;Risk Prediction Initiative&lt;/em&gt;, Universidad Complutense de Madrid. &lt;a href=&quot;http://webs.ucm.es/info/tropical/selga-ii.html&quot;&gt;webs.ucm.es/info/tropical/selga-ii.html.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Tong, W.K. “CHINESE PLAYS: Theatrical Performance At Ko Shing PROGRAMME SUMMARY.” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941),&lt;/em&gt; 8 January 1946. &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1535700201/9565F78882244E0FPQ/10?accountid=1454&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1535700201/9565F78882244E0FPQ/10?accountid=1454&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Variety Entertainment. “CHINESE THEATRICAL SHOW AIDS B.W.O.F: Large Sum Expected From Tai Ping Performances.” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941),&lt;/em&gt; 17 January 1940. &lt;a href=&quot;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1760126135/606B0DBEFBB84088PQ/14?accountid=14548&quot;&gt;https://search-proquest-com.eproxy.lib.hku.hk/hnpsouthchinamorningpost/docview/1760126135/606B0DBEFBB84088PQ/14?accountid=14548&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Unrecognisable Bard: Amalgamating the Colonizer and the Colonized Through Theatre</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/singapore/dutch%20east%20indies/2020/08/14/charmaine-chan/"/>
   <updated>2020-08-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/singapore/dutch%20east%20indies/2020/08/14/charmaine-chan</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Established by an Indian Muslim businessman, Bai Kassim, in 1902, the Bangsawan troupe Wayang Kassim performed in various parts of Malaya, Sumatra and Singapore. Mr Kassim also later in his life became the proprietor of Theatre Royal and it became the go-to destination for accommodating other visiting troupes. In colonial times, “the troupe [Wayang Kassim] performed different types of plays to attract ethnically diverse audience,”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; but the type of performances by the Wayang Kassim that takes precedence in this paper would be that of Shakespearean tragedies. It is a common perception for students of literature nowadays consider Shakespeare as something that is of absolute value and that needs to be approached and addressed with reverence. But the theatre troupe of Wayang Kassim overturned the modern perception of how Shakespeare is regarded and instead works of the highly regarded Bard were utilized with versatility to suit audiences overseas. Wayang Kassim’s unorthodox methods at reproducing the classical plays of Shakespeare succeeds in giving new life to the plays and makes it a form of approachable entertainment to audiences that are not Europeans. This is also achieved by the incorporation of aspects of different regional cultures, such as Dutch actors, Malay costume and dialects that inspired the troupe during its travels. In this process, works of Shakespeare are used by the Wayang Kassim to feature local cultures of Malaysia, it is also in a way a testament to how theatre is a medium that reflects the dynamics of a community. In this paper, adaptations of Shakespeare’s plays for the Malaysian stage by Wayang Kassim directors and playwrights will be examined for the value that it contributes to colonial Singapore’s social environment as well as the influences on modern theatre in Singapore. I have referred to primary archival sources from Singaporean newspaper databases, especially news articles that feature the Wayang Kassim theatre troupe and their comical productions of Shakespearean plays presented as Bangsawan. This paper aims to demonstrate how the theatre troupe of Wayang Kassim interconnects different cultures through the reinvention of traditional plays and in so doing the proscenium theatre is internationalized as it extends beyond European countries that are familiar with the format to more regions that are able to inject cultural elements that are more familiar to them. In sum, Wayang Kassim’s subversion of the traditional tragic plot makes Shakespeare’s works amenable to other alterations that incorporate cultures of Southeast Asia (SEA) and therefore amalgamate cultures of the colonizer and the colonized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;wayang-kassim-productions-of-shakespearean-plays&quot;&gt;Wayang Kassim Productions of Shakespearean Plays&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The troupe first performed in Singapore in 1904 with a production of &lt;em&gt;Othello.&lt;/em&gt; Last performed in Singapore in 1909, staged various Shakespearean plays in Malay and many other Malay and Indonesian plays.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; The interest that this paper takes in the Wayang Kassim was initially brought on by the troupe’s first production of Shakespeare’s &lt;em&gt;Othello&lt;/em&gt; in 1908. This review of the performance highlights the various comical elements that the troupe’s playwright attached to the original play. This is quite an unconventional take on interpreting the revenge tragedy that is &lt;em&gt;Othello&lt;/em&gt;. But as later research has shown, this is a very common approach when it comes to plays that are staged by Wayang Kassim. In an untitled Singaporean news article that featured&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; it mentions how Wayang Kassim, as a troupe, generally “has the happy faculty of turning tragedy into comedy, which seems to take immensely with its patrons, who were apparently, more than delighted with the &lt;em&gt;Malay interpretation&lt;/em&gt; of Shakespeare’s great play”.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; The label of this play being a production of Shakespeare with Malay interpretations suggests that there various Malaysian culture that emerges from the midst of a Shakespearean play, it is almost as if the works of Shakespeare is further manipulated into a form of its own for the sake of being filled and incorporated with indigenous elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The incorporation of foreign cultural elements in the 1908 &lt;em&gt;Othello&lt;/em&gt; was not a singular event of theatre providing a platform for amalgamating different cultures and attempt to represent the colonial social environment. In fact, “this departure from the original plot was a common feature of bangsawan Shakespeare.”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt; For example, in a 1904 production of Hamlet, the troupe dressed “the pensive Dane in Malay dress.”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt; It was not only Malaysian culture, Wayang Kassim also acknowledge the role Singapore plays as a multicultural hub in terms of the language that they would perform in, “[t]he popular songs and musical numbers of the Wayang Kassim were not only performed in Malay, but also in English, Singhalese and Tamil.”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref6&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt; In a production of The Merchant of Venice, a Dutch actor plays the character Shylock and while “[the actor] himself will speak his lines in his native language, but the rest of the company will interpret their parts in English,”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref7&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt; various sources have indicated that the troupe’s reproductions of the Bard’s work “bore practically no resemblance to the play[s] known to Europeans, and yet Wayang Kassim’s performances were immensely well received.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In colonial times, life was considered to be quite dull. In November 1896, &lt;em&gt;The Straits Times&lt;/em&gt; even “lamented the lack of a general social club in Singapore for ‘all the ordinary common or garden men among us’.”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref8&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt; This is a comment towards the lack of financially available entertainment for the common men, as means of entertainment such as opium smoking were only available to &lt;em&gt;towkay&lt;/em&gt; (boss) and not to mention addictions were a quick way to loose one’s job and accommodation. So many would turn to the outdoor theatre for entertainment both for leisure and for an escape of the over-crowded housing situations. Mr. Kassim’s “Theatre Royal on North Bridge Road became a popular venue for daily evening performances of Shakespearean plays in Malay.”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref9&quot;&gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt; This could partly be considered why playwrights of Wayang Kassim actively seek to inject comical elements to famous plays and why they ran with the conviction that it would be welcomed by the Malaysian public. It was not merely because as a Bangsawan performing group that they were to comply with the tone of informality that is expected from Malay Opera but also because the Wayang Kassim troupe “in their method of serving up Shakespeare, do much to brighten [Singapore’s] otherwise dull existence.”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref10&quot;&gt;[10]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-reflection-of-globalization-as-seen-in-wayang-kassim-theatre&quot;&gt;The Reflection of Globalization as Seen in Wayang Kassim Theatre&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As previously mentioned, the performances put on by Wayang Kassim was highly inclusive of other cultures in their reproduction of Shakespeare. In fact, effort were made by founder of the troupe, Bai Kassim, to “employ several Dutch Eurasian and Sundanese actresses in 1903 who almost certainly had performed previously in Komedie Stamboel troupes”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref11&quot;&gt;[11]&lt;/a&gt; for the sake of the craft and the faithful representation of foreign cultures. This is not only to cater to the needs of diverse ethnicity in the audience as they are “as multicultural as the plays [that Wayang Kassim] performed, which consisted of Malays, Chinese, Indians and ‘a good sprinkling of Europeans’ who tried to escape the boredom of Singaporean nights.”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref12&quot;&gt;[12]&lt;/a&gt; But it was also a way of representing the contemporary society. The art form that is the theatre is tied to the needs and interests of distinct social, ethnic groups that is within the performer’s target audience. Wayang Kassim encapsulates with the medium of theatre, the international hub that was Singapore. Though the productions of Shakespearean plays were not faithful representations of the original work, they stood to represent a mix of culture in the contemporary society. Their success in doing so is testified by various primary sources which showed that Wayang Kassim was “popular with a very large section of the population … And once, even the governor of Singapore graced a performance together with a visiting US admiral.”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref13&quot;&gt;[13]&lt;/a&gt; As Malay theatre was influenced by the business role that Singapore played as an international hub among the British colony, the practice of theatre performance is also effectively a reflection of the global economy at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The significance in the research of how Wayang Kassim produced Shakespeare’s plays is that it indicates an indigenous expression through theatre and what more is that there is proof suggesting that the practice of expressing of local culture persisted beyond theatre. Enthusiasts of the Bangsawan theatre persisted through the decline of the industry during WWII, various efforts were made to revive the performing art, which made onto showings through new mediums such as the television and videotapes.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref14&quot;&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt; Wayang Kassim’s practice in bangsawan utilizes known stories of Shakespeare and involves various indigenous culture, which pushes theatre towards an engagement with the contemporary society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; Nadi Tofighian, “Mapping ‘the whirligig of amusements’ in olonial Southeast Asia,” &lt;em&gt;Journal of Southeast Asian Studies&lt;/em&gt;, 49, no. 2, 2018, 277–96, 278-9.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; Philip Smith, &lt;em&gt;Shakespeare in Singapore: Performance, Education, and Culture&lt;/em&gt; (Routledge, 2020), 2.2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; “Untitled,” &lt;em&gt;The Straits Times&lt;/em&gt;, 10 August 1908, 6. https://eresources.nlb.gov.sg/newspapers/Digitised/Article/straitstimes19080810-1.2.39?ST=1&amp;amp;AT=filter&amp;amp;K=tragedy Wayang Kassim&amp;amp;KA=tragedy Wayang Kassim&amp;amp;DF=&amp;amp;DT=&amp;amp;Display=0&amp;amp;AO=false&amp;amp;NPT=&amp;amp;L=&amp;amp;CTA=&amp;amp;NID=&amp;amp;CT=&amp;amp;WC=&amp;amp;YR=&amp;amp;QT=tragedy,wayang,kassim&amp;amp;oref=article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt; Alexander C. Y. Huang, and Charles Stanley. Ross, &lt;em&gt;Shakespeare in Hollywood, Asia, and Cyberspace&lt;/em&gt; (West Lafayette, IN: Purdue University Press, 2010), 141.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt; “Hamlet in Malay,” &lt;em&gt;The Straits Times&lt;/em&gt;, 2 March 1904, 1. https://eresources.nlb.gov.sg/newspapers/Digitised/Article/straitstimes19040302-1.2.5?ST=1&amp;amp;AT=filter&amp;amp;K=tragedy Wayang Kassim&amp;amp;KA=tragedy Wayang Kassim&amp;amp;DF=&amp;amp;DT=&amp;amp;Display=0&amp;amp;AO=false&amp;amp;NPT=&amp;amp;L=&amp;amp;CTA=&amp;amp;NID=&amp;amp;CT=&amp;amp;WC=&amp;amp;YR=1904&amp;amp;QT=tragedy,wayang,kassim&amp;amp;oref=article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref6&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt; Jan van der Putten, and Mary Kilcline Cody, &lt;em&gt;Lost Times and Untold Tales from the Malay&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;World&lt;/em&gt; (Singapore: NUS Press, 2011), 231.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref7&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt; “A Dutch Shylock,” &lt;em&gt;The Straits Times&lt;/em&gt;, 14 November 1912, 3. https://eresources.nlb.gov.sg/newspapers/Digitised/Article/straitstimes19121114-1.2.7?ST=1&amp;amp;AT=filter&amp;amp;K=shakespearean&amp;amp;KA=shakespearean&amp;amp;DF=&amp;amp;DT=&amp;amp;Display=0&amp;amp;AO=false&amp;amp;NPT=&amp;amp;L=&amp;amp;CTA=&amp;amp;NID=&amp;amp;CT=&amp;amp;WC=&amp;amp;YR=1912&amp;amp;QT=shakespearean&amp;amp;oref=article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref8&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt; Hermes. “Singapore Social,” &lt;em&gt;The Straits Times&lt;/em&gt;, 19 January 2016, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.straitstimes.com/singapore/singapore-social&quot;&gt;www.straitstimes.com/singapore/singapore-social&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref9&quot;&gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt; “Investigating History: Colonial Singapore (1819-1941),” &lt;em&gt;National Heritage Board&lt;/em&gt;, www.nhb.gov.sg/nationalmuseum/-/media/nms2017/documents/school-programmes/teachers-hi-resource-unit-2-colonial-singapore.pdf?la=en.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref10&quot;&gt;[10]&lt;/a&gt; C.V.H., “Othello in Malayu,” &lt;em&gt;The Singapore Free Press and Mercantile Advertiser&lt;/em&gt;, 12 November 1908, 6, https://eresources.nlb.gov.sg/newspapers/Digitised/Article/singfreepresswk19081112-1.2.93?ST=1&amp;amp;AT=filter&amp;amp;K=shakespearean play&amp;amp;KA=shakespearean play&amp;amp;DF=&amp;amp;DT=&amp;amp;Display=0&amp;amp;AO=false&amp;amp;NPT=&amp;amp;L=&amp;amp;CTA=&amp;amp;NID=&amp;amp;CT=&amp;amp;WC=&amp;amp;YR=1908&amp;amp;QT=shakespearean,play&amp;amp;oref=article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref11&quot;&gt;[11]&lt;/a&gt; Putten and Cody, 231.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref12&quot;&gt;[12]&lt;/a&gt; Ibid, 230.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref13&quot;&gt;[13]&lt;/a&gt; “Native Bandmanns,” &lt;em&gt;The Singapore Free Press and Mercantile Advertiser&lt;/em&gt;, 14 October 1910, 1, https://eresources.nlb.gov.sg/newspapers/Digitised/Article/singfreepressb19101014-1.2.3?ST=1&amp;amp;AT=filter&amp;amp;K=Wayang shakespeare&amp;amp;KA=Wayang shakespeare&amp;amp;DF=&amp;amp;DT=&amp;amp;Display=0&amp;amp;AO=false&amp;amp;NPT=&amp;amp;L=&amp;amp;CTA=&amp;amp;NID=&amp;amp;CT=&amp;amp;WC=&amp;amp;YR=1910&amp;amp;QT=wayang,shakespeare&amp;amp;oref=article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref14&quot;&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt; “To Be or Not to Be in Bangsawan,” &lt;em&gt;The Strait Times&lt;/em&gt;, 26 May 1988, 5, https://eresources.nlb.gov.sg/newspapers/Digitised/Article/straitstimes19880526-1.2.67.8.1?ST=1&amp;amp;AT=search&amp;amp;k=shakespearean Wayang Kassim&amp;amp;QT=shakespearean,wayang,kassim&amp;amp;oref=article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;Bibliography&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Newspapers and Government Publication:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“A Dutch Shylock.” &lt;em&gt;The Straits Times&lt;/em&gt;, 14 November 1912. https://eresources.nlb.gov.sg/newspapers/Digitised/Article/straitstimes19121114-1.2.7?ST=1&amp;amp;AT=filter&amp;amp;K=shakespearean&amp;amp;KA=shakespearean&amp;amp;DF=&amp;amp;DT=&amp;amp;Display=0&amp;amp;AO=false&amp;amp;NPT=&amp;amp;L=&amp;amp;CTA=&amp;amp;NID=&amp;amp;CT=&amp;amp;WC=&amp;amp;YR=1912&amp;amp;QT=shakespearean&amp;amp;oref=article.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;C.V.H. “Othello in Malayu.” &lt;em&gt;The Singapore Free Press and Mercantile Advertiser&lt;/em&gt;, 12 November 1908. https://eresources.nlb.gov.sg/newspapers/Digitised/Article/singfreepresswk19081112-1.2.93?ST=1&amp;amp;AT=filter&amp;amp;K=shakespearean play&amp;amp;KA=shakespearean play&amp;amp;DF=&amp;amp;DT=&amp;amp;Display=0&amp;amp;AO=false&amp;amp;NPT=&amp;amp;L=&amp;amp;CTA=&amp;amp;NID=&amp;amp;CT=&amp;amp;WC=&amp;amp;YR=1908&amp;amp;QT=shakespearean,play&amp;amp;oref=article.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“Hamlet in Malay.” &lt;em&gt;The Straits Times&lt;/em&gt;, 2 March 1904. https://eresources.nlb.gov.sg/newspapers/Digitised/Article/straitstimes19040302-1.2.5?ST=1&amp;amp;AT=filter&amp;amp;K=tragedy Wayang Kassim&amp;amp;KA=tragedy Wayang Kassim&amp;amp;DF=&amp;amp;DT=&amp;amp;Display=0&amp;amp;AO=false&amp;amp;NPT=&amp;amp;L=&amp;amp;CTA=&amp;amp;NID=&amp;amp;CT=&amp;amp;WC=&amp;amp;YR=1904&amp;amp;QT=tragedy,wayang,kassim&amp;amp;oref=article.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Hermes. “Singapore Social.” &lt;em&gt;The Straits Times&lt;/em&gt;, 19 January 2016, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.straitstimes.com/singapore/singapore-social&quot;&gt;www.straitstimes.com/singapore/singapore-social&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“Investigating History: Colonial Singapore (1819-1941).” &lt;em&gt;National Heritage Board&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;www.nhb.gov.sg/nationalmuseum/-/media/nms2017/documents/school-programmes/teachers-hi-resource-unit-2-colonial-singapore.pdf?la=en.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“Native Bandmanns.” &lt;em&gt;The Singapore Free Press and Mercantile Advertiser&lt;/em&gt;, 14 October 1910. https://eresources.nlb.gov.sg/newspapers/Digitised/Article/singfreepressb19101014-1.2.3?ST=1&amp;amp;AT=filter&amp;amp;K=Wayang shakespeare&amp;amp;KA=Wayang shakespeare&amp;amp;DF=&amp;amp;DT=&amp;amp;Display=0&amp;amp;AO=false&amp;amp;NPT=&amp;amp;L=&amp;amp;CTA=&amp;amp;NID=&amp;amp;CT=&amp;amp;WC=&amp;amp;YR=1910&amp;amp;QT=wayang,shakespeare&amp;amp;oref=article.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“To Be or Not to Be in Bangsawan.” &lt;em&gt;The Strait Times&lt;/em&gt;, 26 May 1988. https://eresources.nlb.gov.sg/newspapers/Digitised/Article/straitstimes19880526-1.2.67.8.1?ST=1&amp;amp;AT=search&amp;amp;k=shakespearean Wayang Kassim&amp;amp;QT=shakespearean,wayang,kassim&amp;amp;oref=article.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“Untitled.” &lt;em&gt;The Straits Times&lt;/em&gt;, 10 August 1908. https://eresources.nlb.gov.sg/newspapers/Digitised/Article/straitstimes19080810-1.2.39?ST=1&amp;amp;AT=filter&amp;amp;K=tragedy Wayang Kassim&amp;amp;KA=tragedy Wayang Kassim&amp;amp;DF=&amp;amp;DT=&amp;amp;Display=0&amp;amp;AO=false&amp;amp;NPT=&amp;amp;L=&amp;amp;CTA=&amp;amp;NID=&amp;amp;CT=&amp;amp;WC=&amp;amp;YR=&amp;amp;QT=tragedy,wayang,kassim&amp;amp;oref=article.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Books and Articles:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Huang, Alexander C. Y., and Charles Stanley. Ross. &lt;em&gt;Shakespeare in Hollywood, Asia, and&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyberspace&lt;/em&gt;. West Lafayette, IN: Purdue University Press, 2010.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Tofighian, Nadi. “Mapping ‘the whirligig of amusements’ in olonial Southeast&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Asia.” &lt;em&gt;Journal of Southeast Asian Studies&lt;/em&gt;, 49, no. 2, 2018, 277–96.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Putten, Jan van der., and Mary Kilcline Cody. &lt;em&gt;Lost Times and Untold Tales from the Malay&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;World&lt;/em&gt;. Singapore: NUS Press, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Smith, Philip. &lt;em&gt;Shakespeare in Singapore: Performance, Education, and Culture&lt;/em&gt;. Routledge, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
