<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Theatre in Colonial South, Southeast, and East Asia</title>
 <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/"/>
 <updated>2020-08-15T02:45:26-04:00</updated>
 <id>http://localhost:4000</id>
 <author>
   <name>Mark Otto</name>
   <email>markdotto@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Missing Footprints: British musical comedy in colonial Hong Kong</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/hong%20kong/2020/08/14/vincent-chu/"/>
   <updated>2020-08-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/hong%20kong/2020/08/14/vincent-chu</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Musical theatre is one of the most popular theatre forms worldwide. Before its reign came a British precursor—musical comedy, which was world-famous in its own right, especially in what was known as the British Empire.[1] Despite its popularity, it had been widely neglected in academia and had been relatively obscured in cultural history.[2] Remnants of it are often ascribed to other forms of entertainment. Its music ‘survived as pub and parlour ballads’ and is associated with the music halls.[3] More than a hundred plays were erroneously ascribed to its American cousin, musical theatre.[4] As an integral component of the British Empire’s past, Hong Kong is expected to have seen its fair share of visiting troupes of this late Victorian and Edwardian art form.[5] Therefore, the city would constitute a good starting point for tracking the footprints of this evanescent giant. In this investigation, I have attempted to document the traces of British musical comedy in colonial Hong Kong through archival research. The findings suggest its lack of success in colonial Hong Kong. Thus, I will attempt to discuss the disparity between the expected popularity and the historical absence of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the surface, colonial Hong Kong was a fertile soil for the theatre trade. Branded the Pearl of the Orient, it served as a nodal point of the British trading networks in Asia. One form of commodities traded amongst others at this nodal point was theatre. In corroboration with the discussion of the modern industrial theatre model during the Edwardian era, troupes from the West indeed valued Hong Kong as a ‘new market [with] potential for profit maximization.’[6] This proposition is exemplified by the competition for venues between Willard’s American Musical Comedy and Opera Company and ‘a troupe of high-class and most accomplished Italian artists.’[7] The Italian troupe intended to leave the Philippines for Hong Kong and perform at the Theatre Royal, City Hall during the window between the two visits of Willard’s company. To monopolize the year at Theatre Royal, Willard booked the venue for October despite the company’s arrival in November. The news article emphasized Hong Kong as ‘fresh-pots’ and that the Italian troupe ‘would have made a deal of money judging from past experiences.’[8] There is no doubt therefore that the theatre trade in colonial Hong Kong was profitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, theatre was crucial to the diasporic community in Hong Kong. From a general perspective, theatre performances allow diasporic communities to ‘survive culturally and socially.’[9] For the British and other European diasporic communities in colonies, theatre performances ‘provided a meeting place where [they] came together to constitute [themselves] as a community.[10] This function of theatre performances is evident in the reportage of the opening night of Zorilla Musical Comedy Comedy’s In Gay Paree in 1905. It clashed with the Governor’s Birthday Ball, which ‘kept a large number of people away’[11] and left it with a “meagre” house’.[12] Possibly as a gesture of courtesy, the Governor attended another performance by the company and his ‘distinguished patronage’ was advertised in the press on that day.[13] It not only hinted that itinerant troupes had a primarily British (or European) diasporic patronage in Hong Kong. More importantly, it revealed the respect or enthusiasm this patronage had for theatre performances as exemplified by the Governor’s patronage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the British diaspora, British musical comedy had more to offer than other genres. It was an instrument of cultural imperialism, which ‘served as a lifeline to the home country’ and allowed the British diaspora to achieve cultural synchronization with their compatriots in Britain.[14] As described in Len Platt’s Musical Comedy on the West End Stage, 1890—1939, British musical comedy was more socially engaged than ‘other forms of late Victorian and Edwardian theatre’ (20). By engaging with issues pertinent to the British society, such as modernity and national identity, British musical comedy served as a ‘vehicle for British ideologies … that [gave] voice to their collective expression as a popular articulation of society and values.’[15] The British diaspora could learn and resonate with the shared sentiments and opinions of the British society in the face of ‘British’ social issues at the turn of the century through British musical comedy. The resonance was strong enough for the Hong Kong Philharmonic Orchestra to stage their own production of the British play The Arcadians in 1937, which was the earliest record of a local musical comedy production in Hong Kong.[16]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite these favourable factors, British musical comedy did not thrive in Hong Kong. There were several factors that could have contributed to this phenomenon with the difficulties in talent recruitment being front and centre. British musical comedy faced many production difficulties. Itinerant troupes had to maximize their profits. The specific production requirement of this novel form prompted musical company troupes to throw in other genres in their repertoire. For instance, the Banvard included a revue, the operetta Katja, the Dancer (which was misidentified as musical comedy), and two American musical comedies in its 1928 season.[17] The Henry Dallas Musical Company was an exception that had performed a season in Hong Kong with a repertoire comprising only British musical comedies.[18] The most prominent difficulty lay in the recruitment of talent. British musical comedy was a departure from the forms of music theatre prior to its conception. Unlike the variety-natured musical halls, a musical play had a continuous narrative. Unlike operetta, it required ‘more natural styles of performance.’[19] As opposed to operetta’s focus on ‘historical romanticism’, British musical comedy was concerned with ‘modernity’ as previously iterated.[20] British musical comedy could be considered a balance between the ‘high art’ of operetta and the ‘common humour’ of music halls. It required realist actors who sang instead of full-fledged singers.[21] This novelty could be an uncertainty for the itinerant troupes. It was more cost-effective to recruit performers from the more traditional forms and staged those forms during tours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, there were other difficulties in the recruitment of talent. The popularity of the form was short-lived for roughly twenty-five years and was struggling before World War I.[22] As realistic as British musical comedy intended to be, it painted the British society in an image of ‘upbeat celebration of modernity’ and ‘[a] naïve assertion of faith in progress and social inclusion.’[23] It failed to capture the insecurities of the British public in the pre-war era and was deemed ‘astonishingly dissonant and quite out of touch in the inter-war period.’[24] The once-progressive form was no longer fashionable and relevant to the sentiments of its British patrons, who started to take a liking to revue. As revue took the crown as the new fashionable musical theatre, talent in Britain began to leave musical comedy for revue.[25] The talent pool became smaller for British musical comedy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although joining itinerant troupes was an option for musical comedy practitioners, the uncertainties associated with touring were dissuasive. In Kathryn Hansen’s article ‘Mapping Melodrama’, the account of the Australian troupe ‘Sarah Lewis’ Dramatic Company’ documented the deaths of several members of this family business due to the harsh conditions during tours.[26] The uncertainties were mostly financial, nonetheless. As troupes often travelled around different colonies, they would be faced with varied climate conditions. For instance, rain would dissuade the theatregoers from attending performances but ‘the rainy season varied from country to country,’[27] Therefore, most tours in Southeast Asia were initially seasonal to avoid the rainy season.[28] Despite employing counter-measures such as putting up ‘rainproof tents’ in later performances, some were occasionally cancelled due to the overwhelming weather.[29] The competition between Willard’s company and the Italian troupe for Theatre Royal best exemplified the financial risk of touring. After its failure in securing a venue, the Italian troupe had to cancel its tour in Hong Kong and disbanded as a result.[30] An alternative was to recruit local talent during the tour, but it would be hardly viable for touring in Hong Kong. The earliest documentation of a local musical comedy production was in 1937, near the end of the genre’s relevance as suggested by Len Platt.[31]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From what I could gather, there was a talent shortage that placed British musical comedy at a disadvantage during its touring days in Hong Kong. However, the favourable conditions for the theatre trade might have in turn benefitted its coevals in thriving financially and welcomed the emergence of film. There are a few perspectives to consider for further investigation. The transformation of musical comedy from the stage to the silver screen was certainly crucial and deserves investigation. As the genre was a recreation of the British sentiments and the society, it was a product of realism and glamour. It is worth looking into the theatrical technologies of colonial Hong Kong and examining whether they were up to the task of producing British musical comedy. Despite its evanescence, British musical comedies were incorporated into music halls’ programmes.[32] It might have survived as artistic heritage in current forms of theatre in Hong Kong as well. It is worth investigating its artistic impact in morphing theatre.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A Chinese Honeymoon—Fetishizing China on Stage</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/hong%20kong/2020/08/14/sharon-k-yuen/"/>
   <updated>2020-08-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/hong%20kong/2020/08/14/sharon-k-yuen</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Chinese Honeymoon&lt;/em&gt;, a musical produced by British company Henry Dallas Musical Comedy Company, was deemed one of the most popular musicals of its times.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; A close examination of the musical itself, the agents involved and the reception towards the show reveals the complex nature of how the East is depicted by the West in the 1900s between the colonizers and colonized societies, particularly that of the United Kingdom, Hong Kong and Singapore.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; This paper argues that the show reveals a certain fetishizing of the idea of the East from the eyes of the West.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focusing on the show as produced in the United Kingdom, Hong Kong and Singapore, this paper will first discuss the content of the show, its reception and its commercial success to reveal the show’s celebrated yet fetishized depiction of an imagined China. After which, we will examine how the show was received and reviewed across different locations, specifically in Hong Kong and Singapore. Throughout, this paper will pay careful attention to how the agents interact within and about the show. It becomes important to consider both the cast and the crew, and, more significantly, the audience and the newspapers reporting on the show to reveal how individual identity is represented and seen through the theatrical event. The global theatrical and commercial reception will be discussed to reveal the power the conceptualization of the Oriental had across the theatrical, and hence, real world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-success&quot;&gt;The Success&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Henry Dallas Musical Comedy Company derived significant theatrical and commercial success with the musical &lt;em&gt;A Chinese Honeymoon&lt;/em&gt;. A review of the show staged in the United Kingdom, published soon after the first showing of the musical on Monday October 10th 1800, lauded the premier with glowing praise, remarking that its first performance proved “an exceedingly good one” with its acting deserving of the “highest praise”, concluding that the show is “well mounted and admirably dressed.”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; The success of the show is evident in the number of times it was put up, having gone beyond a thousand shows at the Strand Theatre and attracted returning audience members who had grown to love seeing the show live.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt; By the 923rd consecutive show, it had already broken the theatre’s record of having a musical play be consecutively put up at the same location.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;  The Strand Theatre’s last show of the musical was numbered as the 1075th show, with the profits not short of six figures and well over the profits made in another famous musical &lt;em&gt;The Belle of New York&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref6&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt;  The show was later staged at the Theatre Royal and was attended by “a large audience”.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref7&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt;  Notably, the newspaper remarked that famously-named individuals were also in attendance, such as “His Excellency and Mrs. May”.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref8&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt;  Similarly, the audience was reported to have been found giving “repeated applause” during the curtain call for many of the cast members.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref9&quot;&gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt;  The importance and success of the play in the United Kingdom becomes immediately evident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disregarding the local success in the United Kingdom, the musical proved a hit worldwide. The mere fact that the Company travelled so wildly via the Norddeutscher liner &lt;em&gt;Konig Sin Luise&lt;/em&gt; is a good indication of its popularity.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref10&quot;&gt;[10]&lt;/a&gt;  Some of the places that the Company had been to included Sri Lanka, India, Singapore and Hong Kong.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref11&quot;&gt;[11]&lt;/a&gt;  Even though the Company performed multiple musical comedies with each tour at each location, &lt;em&gt;Chinese Honeymoon&lt;/em&gt; drew a significant amount of attention, with advertisements and reviews written by the local press in both Singapore and in Hong Kong. The show’s success was evident by its global spread, and, equally as important, its economic success. In 1904, the musical was reported to have yielded 60,000 pounds of clear profits, rendering it a “really successfully play”, with the authors’ share of gold reflected to be on a “regal scale”.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref12&quot;&gt;[12]&lt;/a&gt; Hence, it is undeniable that the ideas that the musical propagated and the world that it represented would easily be taken and spread around the world through such tours, making it significant for us to consider what exactly &lt;em&gt;Chinese Honeymoon&lt;/em&gt; depicted as a honeymoon in China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-show&quot;&gt;The Show&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The musical is set in a fictional, but clearly Chinese, location called Ylang Ylang, where an old-fashioned “Emperor” demands that couples found kissing must be married within 6 hours.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref13&quot;&gt;[13]&lt;/a&gt; The plots rests upon the protagonists of the show, Mr. Pineapple and his wife, a British couple who, “instead of spending their honeymoon in good old England”, opted to “invade the Yellow Man’s Territory.”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref14&quot;&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt; The rising action of the show depends on Mr. Pineapple becoming “compromised” by Chinese girls and Mrs. Pineapple taking revenge by “flirting with the pig-tailed brethren.”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref15&quot;&gt;[15]&lt;/a&gt; As seen through the words quoted from the archives to describe the actions of the West as taking over the actions of the East, such as the active verb of “invade”, a clear narrative of “them”—the East and “us”—the West is delivered through the show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lack of understanding of what it truly means to live in the East can be seen in the stereotypical and meaningless choice of names for the Chinese characters, such as Chippee Chop, Soo-Soo, Yen-Yen, Sing-sing. The fact that the cast is entirely Caucasian brings another issue to the table of representation of who is representing whom and brings the issue of yellow face into question. The same can be said of the lyrical content of the show, such as the first song, titled “In the days of the ancient long ago in a quaint little Chinese town” performed by Soo-Soo and the chorus.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref16&quot;&gt;[16]&lt;/a&gt; Anne Veronica Witchard notes that the lyrics of the musical, such as “chop, chop, chow, chow,/ sing song, sow, sow” are “unremittingly silly”, with “nonsense words” and “strange sounds of an incomprehensible and impossible language”.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref17&quot;&gt;[17]&lt;/a&gt; China, as represented in Chinese Honeymoon, then, is not a real location, but a fictionalized one. All these features point towards a level of ignorance and idealization of what it means to live in the East. Indeed, a review of the show aptly captures the culture of viewing the East as an exotic location: “Of late years we have had a succession of musical plays with rich and glowing Far Eastern setting. They have had a phenomenal popularity, but strangely enough the interest in the songs and daughters of the Flowerly Land never flags.”[18]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idealization in the musical of China, Chinatown and Chinese people as “quaint” and exotic demonstrates that a problematic phenomenon exists of the West infantalizing what it means to live in the East. The British musical and newspaper, and hence likely its audience and its consumers, viewed themselves as, at least, different, if not superior, to Chinese people. The notion of the West being superior to the Chinese can be seen in the many ways in which the musical depicts China as a strange, foreign and potentially barbaric place with unexplained customs and rules. The judgmental lens bring to mind what Edward Said argues about Orientalism in that “the Oriental becomes more Oriental, the Westerner more Western.”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref19&quot;&gt;[19]&lt;/a&gt; Similarly, scholar Dongshen Chang notes that there is a paradox of presence and absence of Chinese-ness in the British representations of China on stage – there was constant attention to China that deviated from China’s own representations of itself.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref20&quot;&gt;[20]&lt;/a&gt; Heidi Holder argues that such stereotypical plots of melodrama and colonial characters enact “an imperialist expansion of British culture.”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref21&quot;&gt;[21]&lt;/a&gt; It becomes clear then that, from Chinese Honeymoon, there was a divergence between how the musical sees the East and what the East actually is like – the East is exoticized in the musical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-tour--people&quot;&gt;The Tour &amp;amp; People&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ironically, even though the musical itself fetishizes the East, the tours of the musical in the East appeared to not have been met with much resistance or criticism in the newspaper archives. The show’s stereotypes are acknowledged but brushed aside by most reviews. In a review in the Hong Kong Weekly Press, the show was described as “light and amusing, and the music tuneful and gay”, so that it was “easy to understand” its popularity and commercial success.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref22&quot;&gt;[22]&lt;/a&gt; In Singapore, the show’s problematic representation of Chinese people is ignored, with a review merely describing the show as “a couple hours of light amusement, by means of pretty face, smart calls…”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref23&quot;&gt;[23]&lt;/a&gt; A reviewer in the  South China Morning Post, simply notes that it is a “bold thing” to put on the show in Hong Kong, and yet defends the show by saying that the jokes do “to some extent give one an idea of the Orientals” and that “if the local coloring is exaggerated, [they] would not have it otherwise.”&lt;a href=&quot;#ref24&quot;&gt;[24]&lt;/a&gt; Although this may be a reflection of dominant English-language use then, it is still strange to have a Hong Kong-based newspaper describe its own location as “Oriental”, a word that ultimately works to fetishize ones location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, besides the unrealistic names given to the Chinese characters of the show, it is worthy to note that the show does not include any Asian cast members, in both the original cast, the touring cast in Singapore and the touring cast in Hong Kong. Yellow-face may very well be used in the show, but this was never acknowledged in the newspapers, nor was the lack of Asian representation discussed. This perhaps points towards the popularity of the show among the Caucasian audiences in the colonies, both in Hong Kong and Singapore. The locations of the shows are also worthy a note, given that the Dallas Company staged the musical in prominent locations, such as the City Hall in Hong Kong.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref25&quot;&gt;[25]&lt;/a&gt; Given that the advertisement and reviews of the shows was found in English newspapers and the show itself was put on in English, it seemed likely that there would be a predominately English-speaking, and likely Caucasian, population in attendance. The largely positive reviews of a musical that ridicules what it means to be Chinese indicates the lack of Chinese and local perspectives both in the show and of the show. The musical theatre may hence be a more colonial, and likely privileged location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As seen from the newspaper archives of the show, the presence and voice of Chinese people were absent from the show, whether it be in the substantive content, the representation from the cast, crew and possibly the audience. The teleportation of the racially insensitive musical from a predominately upper-class Caucasian community to predominately Chinese societies has brought issues regarding race and class to the forefront of the discussion of what it means to be seen as the East. &lt;em&gt;Chinese Honeymoon&lt;/em&gt; reveals a particularly romanticized lens of what it means to be seen as Chinese by the West and the problematic notions this fetishization reveals in terms of racism, class and power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; A Chinese Honeymoon, a musical comedy in two acts, music by Howard Talbot, book and lyrics by George Dance, Chappell &amp;amp; Co. Ltd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ref2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; This approach is one referred to by Thomas Postlewait as one possible way of studying theatre historicity; Thomas Postlewait, The Cambridge Introduction to Theatre Historiography (Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 2012), 9–21.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; “A CHINESE HONEYMOON”, Era, 21 October 1899, https://link.gale.com/apps/doc/
BB3202531212/BNCN?u=hku&amp;amp;sid=BNCN&amp;amp;xid=7a68e87a.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt; THE PROMPTER. “‘P. I. P.’ PALYGOER,” Penny Illustrated Paper, 26 March 1904, 206, https://link.gale.com/apps/doc/BA3207741371/BNCN?u=hku&amp;amp;sid=BNCN&amp;amp;xid=37f95da6,.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref5&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ref5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/a&gt; Article 1 – No Title, South China Morning Post (1903-1941), 26 February 1904,
ProQuest Historical Newspapers: South China Morning Post, 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref6&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ref6&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/a&gt; “A CHINESE HONEYMOON”, Era, 21 October 1899. https://link.gale.com/apps/doc/
BB3202531212/BNCN?u=hku&amp;amp;sid=BNCN&amp;amp;xid=7a68e87a; Hong Kong Daily Press, 24 June 1904, NPDP19040624.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref7&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ref7&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/a&gt; THEATRE ROYAL: “A Chinese Honeymoon,” South China Morning Post (1903-1941), 24 February 1904, 5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref8&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ref8&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/a&gt; Ibid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref9&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ref9&quot;&gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/a&gt; “THE FOOTLIGHTS,” Northern Echo, 4 September 1900, https://link.gale.com/apps/
doc/BA3200280535/BNCN?u=hku&amp;amp;sid=BNCN&amp;amp;xid=cb36e745.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref10&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ref10&quot;&gt;[10]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/a&gt; “THE DALLAS COMPANY,” South China Morning Post (1903-1941), Feb 23, 1904, 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref12&quot;&gt;[12]&lt;/a&gt; Ibid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref13&quot;&gt;[13]&lt;/a&gt; “Article 6 – No Title”, South China Morning Post (1903-1941), 23 April 1904, 5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref14&quot;&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt; “A Chinese Honeymoon,” The Singapore Free Press and Mercantile Advertiser (Weekly), 15 June 1904, 374.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref15&quot;&gt;[15]&lt;/a&gt; “THE FOOTLIGHTS”, Northern Echo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref16&quot;&gt;[16]&lt;/a&gt; “A CHINESE HONEYMOON”, Era.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref17&quot;&gt;[17]&lt;/a&gt; “Synopsis,” Talbot, Dance, The Guide to Musical Theatre, http://www.guidetomusicaltheatre.com/shows_c/chinese_honeymoon.html.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref18&quot;&gt;[18]&lt;/a&gt; Anne Veronica Witchard, Thomas Burke’s dark chinoiserie: Limehouse nights and the queer spell of Chinatown (Farnham, Surrey: Ashgate Publishing, Ltd., 2009), 82.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref19&quot;&gt;[19]&lt;/a&gt; “THE FOOTLIGHTS”, Northern Echo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref20&quot;&gt;[20]&lt;/a&gt; Edward W. Said, Orientalism: Edward W. Said (New York: Vintage Books, 2003).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref21&quot;&gt;[21]&lt;/a&gt; Dongshin Chang, Representing China on the Historical London Stage: From Orientalism to Intercultural Performance (NYC/Abingdon-on-Thames: Routledge, 2015).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref22&quot;&gt;[22]&lt;/a&gt; Heidi J Holder, “Melodrama, Realism and Empire on the British Stage,” in Acts of Supremacy: The British Empire and the Stage, 1790-1930, ed. Bratton, 1991, 141-2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref23&quot;&gt;[23]&lt;/a&gt; “The War Between Japan and Russia,” Hong Kong Weekly Press 27 February 1904.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref24&quot;&gt;[24]&lt;/a&gt; “A Chinese Honeymoon,” The Singapore Free Press.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref26&quot;&gt;[25]&lt;/a&gt; “THE DALLAS COMPANY,” South China Morning Post (1903-1941).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ref26&quot;&gt;[26]&lt;/a&gt; Ibid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;Bibliography&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A CHINESE HONEYMOON.” &lt;em&gt;Era&lt;/em&gt;, 21 October 1899. British Library Newspapers, &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.gale.com/apps/doc/BB3202531212/BNCN?u=hku&amp;amp;sid=BNCN&amp;amp;xid=7a68e87a&quot;&gt;https://link.gale.com/apps/doc/BB3202531212/BNCN?u=hku&amp;amp;sid=BNCN&amp;amp;xid=7a68e87a.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“THE FOOTLIGHTS.” &lt;em&gt;Northern Echo&lt;/em&gt;, 4 September 1900. &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.gale.com/apps/doc/BA3200280535/BNCN?u=hku&amp;amp;sid=BNCN&amp;amp;xid=cb36e745&quot;&gt;https://link.gale.com/apps/doc/BA3200280535/BNCN?u=hku&amp;amp;sid=BNCN&amp;amp;xid=cb36e745&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A Chinese Honeymoon.” &lt;em&gt;The Singapore Free Press and Mercantile Advertiser (Weekly)&lt;/em&gt;, 15 June 1904.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Article 6 – No Title.” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 23 April 1904.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Synopsis,” Talbot, Dance, &lt;em&gt;The Guide to Musical Theatre&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guidetomusicaltheatre.com/shows_c/chinese_honeymoon.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.guidetomusicaltheatre.com/shows_c/chinese_honeymoon.htm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“THE DALLAS COMPANY,” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 23 February 1904.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The War Between Japan and Russia.” &lt;em&gt;Hong Kong Weekly Press&lt;/em&gt;, 27 February 1904.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Article 1 – No Title. &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 26 February 1904.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chang, Dongshin. &lt;em&gt;Representing China on the Historical London Stage: From Orientalism to Intercultural Performance&lt;/em&gt;. NYC/Abingdon-on-Thames: Routledge, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holder, Heidi J. “Melodrama, Realism and Empire on the British Stage.” In &lt;em&gt;Acts of Supremacy&lt;/em&gt;, edited by J.S. Bratton. Manchester: Manchester University Press, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hong Kong Daily Press,&lt;/em&gt; 24 June 1904. NPDP19040624.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Postlewait, Thomas. &lt;em&gt;The Cambridge Introduction to Theatre Historiography&lt;/em&gt;. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 2012, 9-21.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Said, Edward W. &lt;em&gt;Orientalism: Edward W. Said&lt;/em&gt;. New York: Vintage Books, 2003.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talbot, Howard, George Dance. &lt;em&gt;A Chinese Honeymoon, a musical comedy in two acts&lt;/em&gt;. Hopwood &amp;amp; Crew, Limited, 1901.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THE PROMPTER. “‘P. I. P.’ PALYGOER.” &lt;em&gt;Penny Illustrated Paper&lt;/em&gt;, 26 March 1904.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THEATRE ROYAL: “A Chinese Honeymoon,” &lt;em&gt;South China Morning Post (1903-1941)&lt;/em&gt;, 24 February 1904.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Witchard, Anne Veronica. &lt;em&gt;Thomas Burke’s dark chinoiserie: Limehouse nights and the queer spell of Chinatown&lt;/em&gt;. Farnham, Surrey: Ashgate Publishing, Ltd., 2009.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
